<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info> Frederick Ernest Andrews, 16 October 1917, France Born: 15 November 1879, Regiment:
        Railway Operation Division, Royal Engineers, Regiment number: 218857, Rank: Sapper, Returned
        to office: 26 May 1919, Retired: 15 November 1939 Transcript </info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1917-10-16">16 October 1917</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Mr Slater</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Just a few lines to let you know how things are going with me, I have been going to write to
        before this, but on each occasion I have had to postpone it for some reason or other. I have
        been at this place since April. It is a fairly large city and has at one time been <emote
            type="positive">a very nice place</emote>, but it is now a heap of ruins, not a
        habitable house anywhere and no civilians, it is the nearest railhead to this part of the
        line and when we first came here things were pretty lively, but Fritz is gradually being
        pushed back here and has not troubled us for some time now I don't mind if he has forgotten
        we're here. Naldrett, Dawson and Anglesey and several other Audit chaps were up here a short
        time ago, but their detachment has now been moved to another part of the line, they are on
        the Light Railway and shift about more. <emote type="positive">It was nice to meet some of
            the old office pals again and I spent several pleasant hours with them while they were
            here</emote>, for I am the only G.W. man in this detachment. McMeeken is in the Railway
        Transport Officer's office about three miles from here and I see him occasionally. <emote
            type="negative">I was very sorry to hear of the deaths of Pond and Woodhams and no doubt
            there are other casualties amongst our office chaps but I seldom hear any office news.
            Our family has had to pay the penalty of war that so many thousands of families have
            done, for I am now the only one out here, <factor type="trauma">one brother has just
                been discharged after nine months in hospital</factor>, <factor type="battle">the
                second one was killed at Ypres about a month ago</factor> and <factor type="trauma"
                >the third is now in a London hospital with a bad shrapnel wound in the
                thigh</factor>.</emote> I have had a variety of jobs, including navvy's work,
        carrying rails and sleepers, guard, point oiler and various other jobs. <emote
            type="positive">I am now a checker and number taker which job suits me much better, for
            it combines a lot of indoor clerical work with outdoor checking and now that we have to
            face another winter out here, it will be something to spend a little of my time indoors
            for I still have memories of last winter under canvas, but I shall not be so badly off
            this winter for <factor type="conditions">we are living in railway vans which will be
                much warmer</factor>. </emote>I have now been in France nearly nine months and
            <emote type="negative"> there does not appear to be any prospect of leave, for there are
            more here who have been eighteen months without leave and at the rate the R.O.D. men are
            going at present it will be well into next year before my turn comes.</emote> I
        understand that north London has suffered rather badly in the recent air raids but I hope
        you came through all right. My wife and family have had to get away from home, for it was
        upsetting their nerves and <emote type="positive">I am pleased to think that they are out of
            the danger zone. I am keeping fairly fit in health and always manage to keep cheery,
            which wants a bit of doing sometimes <factor type="conditions">especially now the muddy
                season has started</factor>, but let's hope this will be our last out here and by
            this time next year we may be all settling down to civilian life again.</emote>
    </p>
    <p>Please remember me to Mr Wood, Bert Hunt and all other Audit friends.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours sincerely</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">F.E. Andrews'</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
