        <div type="letter">
            <dateline><name type="person">Teddy Ashton</name>, <date when="1916-05-06">May 6th,
                    1916</date> Sailor stationed in <name type="place">Russian
                Lapland</name></dateline>
            <!--  source: https://www.iwm.org.uk/history/letters-to-loved-ones-->
            <opener>
                <salue>Dear <name type="person">Gertie,</name></salue>
            </opener>
            <p> I have written two or three times recently so you may get them together. <emotion
                    type="negative">We have been very busy for the last few weeks and have got
                    through a great amount of work.</emotion>
                <emotion type="postive">We are much better off again as regards potatoes and other
                    food stuffs for we have had a great quantity of stores.</emotion> I fancy we
                shall be here for a time yet anyway it looks like it with such a quantity of stores
                aboard. You will see I am telling you the same things over and over again.<emotion
                    type="negative"> At least I know I have told you them once or twice but
                    everything about is all of a sameness kind of thing.</emotion>
                <factor type="sense">Ships here there and everywhere now.</factor> But soon we shall
                have a move that is when we can get through the White Sea. We shall have to look
                after all the shipping. <factor type="condition">The snow is fast disappearing
                    now.</factor> I came across an article in a paper the other day about this
                district and it said that 14 or 15 years ago bears used to roam around hear [sic],
                but <factor type="sense">there seems to be nothing around now excepting the wild
                    fowl, which are very numorous.</factor> I believe salmon are numerous at certain
                times of the year. <date when="1916-05-02,1916-05-03">The 2nd and 3rd of May</date>
                we had a <emotion type="negative">terrific</emotion>
                <factor type="condition">snow blizzard.</factor> We should have left the ship to go
                away and do some work on another ship but <emotion type="negative">we could not get
                    away from our ship <factor type="condition">it was so rough</factor></emotion>.
                    <factor type="sense"> We have no night now, the sun goes down but it never goes
                    dark, it is eternally daylight.</factor> Of course I told you we have had an
                entire change round and I have a new job now, part of the ship. <emotion
                    type="positive">I have not half the time I used to have but I enjoy the robust
                    work much better and I get to see much more with working away.</emotion> We get
                up at 6.30 and work until 1.00 so we put a few hours in don't we. That is when we
                are working away. Did you get the £1-0-0 I remitted? Let me know. I have remitted
                another £3-0-0 this month. Let me know if you receive this also. I shall probably
                send a little more next month or later. Don't hold the paper money. Bank it or keep
                it by you in gold until I come home. Tell Dad I shall to him as soon as I can get
                enough to tell him about. Give my best love to everyone at home, I often think about
                you all.</p>
            <closer>
                <salute>I am yours ever</salute>,<signed><signedname type="person">
                        Ted.</signedname>
                </signed>
            </closer>
        </div>
