Teddy Ashton, May 6th, 1916
Sailor stationed in Russian Lapland
https://www.iwm.org.uk/history/letters-to-loved-ones

Dear Gertie, I have written two or three times recently so you may get them together.
We have been very busy for the last few weeks and have got through a great amount of work.
We are much better off again as regards potatoes and other food stuffs for we have had a great quantity of stores.
I fancy we shall be here for a time yet anyway it looks like it with such a quantity of stores aboard.
You will see I am telling you the same things over and over again.
At least I know I have told you them once or twice but everything about is all of a sameness kind of thing.
Ships here there and everywhere now. But soon we shall have a move that is when we can get through the White Sea.
We shall have to look after all the shipping.
The snow is fast disappearing now.
I came across an article in a paper the other day about this district and it said that 14 or 15 years ago bears used to roam around hear [sic],
but there seems to be nothing around now excepting the wild fowl, which are very numorous.
I believe salmon are numerous at certain times of the year.
The 2nd and 3rd of May we had a terrific snow blizzard.
We should have left the ship to go away and do some work on another ship but we could not get away from our ship it was so rough.
We have no night now, the sun goes down but it never goes dark, it is eternally daylight.
Of course I told you we have had an entire change round and I have a new job now, part of the ship.
I have not half the time I used to have but I enjoy the robust work much better and I get to see much more with working away.
We get up at 6.30 and work until 1.00 so we put a few hours in don't we. That is when we are working away.
Did you get the £1-0-0 I remitted? Let me know. I have remitted another £3-0-0 this month.
Let me know if you receive this also. I shall probably send a little more next month or later.
Don't hold the paper money. Bank it or keep it by you in gold until I come home.
Tell Dad I shall to him as soon as I can get enough to tell him about.
Give my best love to everyone at home, I often think about you all.
I am yours ever, Ted.'
