<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Harry Beaumont, 18 August 1916, Rawalpindi, India. Born: 17 October 1873, Regiment: 1/6
        East Surrey Regiment, Regiment number: 2297, Rank: Quarter Master Sergeant, Died: 1952
        Transcript</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-08-18">August 18th</date>
            <name type="place">Rawalpindi, India</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Bertie,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Just a few lines to let you know how we are getting on out here, I forgot when I last wrote
        you last and what news I told you. We marched down from the hills, 9,000 feet up in the
        Himalaya Mountains last October to Rawalpindi, then shortly afterwards out to camp returning
        just before Xmas. In February I obtained a furlough and <emote type="positive"> had a fine
            tour of places of interest, down to Delhi then right across India to Calcutta, had
            several letters of introduction from brother Freemasons to awfully nice people there and
            had a most enjoyable time, spent a few days at Agra on the return journey, travelled
            roughly just over 3,000 miles with several nights in the train.</emote> A few days after
        returning the regiment was <factor type="prep">placed under orders to march 83 miles to
            Noushera on the frontier border</factor>, where over 10,000 British and native troops
        were concentrated, a similar number at Peshawar farther down the frontier, in readiness for
        threatened trouble with the Afghans, whom German intriguers had been amongst. <emote
            type="negative">Noushera was a cruel place, nothing but a dust heap at the foot of the
            mountain.</emote>
        <factor type="prep">We spent several weeks there, training in mountain warfare</factor>,
            <emote type="negative">my word, it was chronic, <factor type="conditions">the terrific
                heat</factor> and the awful climbing for miles day after day, with all transport on
            mules and camels through the rocky mountain passes.</emote> At one bivouac we
        encountered <factor type="conditions">bad water</factor>, and about <factor type="trauma"
            >forty of our fellows went down with enteric fever [typhoid]</factor>. One died, but the
        others pulled through as they had been inoculated; <emote type="positive">a wonderful thing
            inoculation has proved to be in India.</emote></p>
    <p><emote type="positive">Well in spite of the hard time, we returned to Rawalpindi in fine
            condition</emote> after the Afghan trouble had subsided for the time being, it is always
        liable to break out at any moment and we are always in readiness to move at any time.</p>
    <p>Then we changed to another barracks in Rawalpindi in April, and have been stationed on the
        plains all the summer. <emote type="negative">
            <factor type="conditions">The heat has been intense</factor>; one never goes outside
            after 10am; after tiffin at 1 o'clock the barracks and in fact everywhere is dead to the
            world until between 5 and 6pm</emote>, when sports such as tennis, cricket hockey and
        swimming at the baths are possible.</p>

    <p>
        <factor type="conditions">Every soldier has a punkah (fan) swinging over his bed all night
            and during the hours off duty during the day. Many men sleep out on the barrack square
            on their beds at night. During the past few weeks the monsoon has been on, with
            torrential rain which I would fail to describe.</factor>
        <emote type="negative">Now the intense heat of the sun is draining the moisture out of the
            earth with the result that it is like living in the moist fern house at Kew
            Gardens,</emote>
        <emote type="negative">only worse</emote>, <factor type="trauma">and many men are being
            bowled over with fever</factor>. <emote type="positive">Ever since arriving at India,
            getting on for two years ago, I have been as fit as a fiddle and enjoyed exceptional
            health</emote>, <emote type="negative">until a fortnight ago, when I was suddenly taken
            ill with <factor type="trauma">sandfly fever, a most painful, lowering form of fever,
            </factor> and was carried to hospital and also found to be suffering from <factor
                type="trauma">pleurisy</factor></emote>. I was in bed several days subsisting on a
        small quantity of milk with the result that when I was allowed to get up I was too weak to
        stand. <emote type="positive">I was discharged after ten days and am getting on quite
            alright now, and am leaving on next furlough to a hill station in the Himalayas shortly
            to recuperate</emote>. In November we are on the move again, <factor type="prep"
            >marching about 80 miles to a big camp, for manoeuvres of several weeks,</factor>
        returning again just before Christmas.<emote type="negative"> But marching eighty miles in
            five days under an Indian sun is very different to cloudy England.</emote> Every
        regiment in India, both regular and territorial, is being heavily reinforced by drafts from
        England. We have had three drafts one consisting of nearly 300 men, then another of 67, now
        another of 84, bringing us up to nearly 1,100 men. There are thousands of British troops,
        mostly Terriers (members of the Territorial army) (there are only eight regular infantry
        regiments left in India) stationed at various frontier places, and all sorts of rumours
        prevalent about a big expedition moving during the next few months, all possible
        preparations are being made for it, well, if the Indian govt. <emote type="negative">make as
            disastrous a muddle of it when the fighting does come off as they made over the
            Mesopotamia campaign, then with foes like the ferocious Afghans there will be a terrible
            price to pay in life, for the country and the <factor type="conditions">terrific
                heat</factor> will be enough without having to fight every inch of the
        way.</emote></p>

    <p><emote type="positive">I had a very interesting letter from Mr Wood some time ago which I
            answered recently, also had one from Mr Price a few days ago.</emote> I can quite
        picture the changes which must have occurred in the staff of the Audit since I left. Of
        course you are over the age limit, so have not been called upon. <emote type="negative">I
            expect if, and when, I do return safely that life in England will seem very different
            under the altered conditions. I shall be glad to get home again and only wish I could
            see a prospect of doing so, with the conclusion of this terrible war.</emote>
        <emote type="positive">I have had a very enjoyable time in India</emote>
        <emote type="negative">(apart from soldiering which I always did enjoy, although I think I
            have had sufficient now)</emote> having made the acquaintance of awfully nice residents
        in 'Pindi, and by virtue of rank, being allowed the privilege of wearing mufti makes it so
        much more comfortable when going out of barracks than being in a tight uniform in the
        climate.</p> 
    
    <p><emote type="positive">I hear regularly from my wife and little one every week. Am
            glad to say they are well.</emote></p>
    
    <p>Please convey my kind regards to all those left in the office
            that I know. Trusting you are all fit and well and that we shall meet again before many
            more months elapse.
    </p>


    <closer>
        <salute>With best wishes Yours most sincerely </salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Harry Beaumont</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
