<div type="letter">
    <dateline><name type="person">Harry Beaumont</name>, <date when="1916-09-18">18 August
            1916</date>,<name type="place"> Rawalpindi, India</name>. Born: 17 October 1873,
            <regiment>Regiment: 1/6 <name type="place">East Surrey</name> Regiment, Regiment number:
            2297</regiment>, Rank: Quarter Master Sergeant, Died: 1952 Transcript</dateline>
    <opener>
        <salute>Dear <name type="person">Bertie</name>,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Just a few lines to let you know how we are getting on out here, I forgot when I last wrote
        you last and what news I told you. We marched down from the hills, 9,000 feet up in the
            <name type="place">Himalaya Mountains</name> last October to <name type="place">
            Rawalpindi</name>, then shortly afterwards out to camp returning just before <date
            when="12-24">Xmas</date>. In February I obtained a furlough and <emotion type="positive"
            > had a fine tour of places of interest, down to <name type="place">Delhi</name> then
            right across <name type="place">India</name> to <name type="place">Calcutta</name>, had
            several letters of introduction from brother Freemasons to awfully nice people there and
            had a most enjoyable time, spent a few days at <name type="place">Agra</name> on the
            return journey, travelled roughly just over 3,000 miles with several nights in the
            train.</emotion> A few days after returning the regiment was <factor type="prep">placed
            under orders to march 83 miles to <name type="place"> Noushera</name> on the frontier
            border</factor>, where over 10,000 British and native troops were concentrated, a
        similar number at <name type="place">Peshawar</name> farther down the frontier, in readiness
        for threatened trouble with the <name type="place">Afghans</name>, whom <name type="place"
            >German</name> intriguers had been amongst. <emotion type="negative"><name type="place"
                >Noushera</name> was a cruel place, nothing but a dust heap at the foot of the
            mountain.</emotion>
        <factor type="prep">We spent several weeks there, training in mountain warfare</factor>,
            <emotion type="negative">my word, it was chronic, <factor type="conditions">the terrific
                heat</factor> and the awful climbing for miles day after day, with all transport on
            mules and camels through the rocky mountain passes.</emotion> At one bivouac we
        encountered <factor type="conditions">bad water</factor>, and about <factor type="trauma"
            >forty of our fellows went down with enteric fever [typhoid]</factor>. One died, but the
        others pulled through as they had been inoculated; <emotion type="positive">a wonderful
            thing inoculation has proved to be in <name type="place">India</name>.</emotion></p>
    <p><emotion type="positive">Well in spite of the hard time, we returned to <name type="place"
                >Rawalpindi</name> in fine condition</emotion> after the <name type="place"
            >Afghan</name> trouble had subsided for the time being, it is always liable to break out
        at any moment and we are always in readiness to move at any time.</p>
    <p>Then we changed to another barracks in <name type="place">Rawalpindi</name> in April, and
        have been stationed on the plains all the summer. <emotion type="negative">
            <factor type="conditions">The heat has been intense</factor>; one never goes outside
            after 10am; after tiffin at 1 o'clock the barracks and in fact everywhere is dead to the
            world until between 5 and 6pm</emotion>, when sports such as tennis, cricket hockey and
        swimming at the baths are possible.</p>
    <p>
        <factor type="condition">Every soldier has a punkah (fan) swinging over his bed all night
            and during the hours off duty during the day. Many men sleep out on the barrack square
            on their beds at night. During the past few weeks the monsoon has been on, with
            torrential rain which I would fail to describe.</factor>
        <emotion type="negative">Now the intense heat of the sun is draining the moisture out of the
            earth with the result that it is like living in the moist fern house at <name
                type="place">Kew Gardens</name>, <emotion type="negative">only worse</emotion>,
                <factor type="trauma">and many men are being bowled over with
            fever</factor></emotion>. <emotion type="positive">Ever since arriving at <name
                type="place">India</name>, getting on for two years ago, I have been as fit as a
            fiddle and enjoyed exceptional health</emotion>, <emotion type="negative">until a
            fortnight ago, when I was suddenly taken ill with <factor type="trauma">sandfly fever, a
                most painful, lowering form of fever, </factor> and was carried to hospital and also
            found to be suffering from <factor type="trauma">pleurisy</factor>. I was in bed several
            days subsisting on a small quantity of milk with the result that when I was allowed to
            get up I was too weak to stand.</emotion>
        <emotion type="positive">I was discharged after ten days and am getting on quite alright
            now, and am leaving on next furlough to a hill station in the <name type="place"
                >Himalayas</name> shortly to recuperate</emotion>. In November we are on the move
        again, <factor type="prep">marching about 80 miles to a big camp, for manoeuvres of several
            weeks,</factor> returning again just before Christmas.<emotion type="negative"> But
            marching eighty miles in five days under an <name type="place">Indian</name> sun is very
            different to cloudy <name type="place">England </name>.</emotion> Every regiment in
            <name type="place"> India</name>, both regular and territorial, is being heavily
        reinforced by drafts from <name type="place">England</name>. We have had three drafts one
        consisting of nearly 300 men, then another of 67, now another of 84, bringing us up to
        nearly 1,100 men. There are thousands of <name type="place">British</name> troops, mostly
        Terriers (members of the Territorial army) (there are only eight regular infantry regiments
        left in <name type="place">India</name>) stationed at various frontier places, and all sorts
        of rumours prevalent about a big expedition moving during the next few months, all possible
        preparations are being made for it, well, if the <name type="place">Indian</name> govt.
            <emotion type="negative">make as disastrous a muddle of it when the fighting does come
            off as they made over the <name type="place">Mesopotamia</name> campaign, then with foes
            like the ferocious Afghans there will be a terrible price to pay in life, for the
            country and the <factor type="conditions">terrific heat</factor> will be enough without
            having to fight every inch of the way.</emotion>
        <emotion type="positive">I had a very interesting letter from <name type="person">Mr
                Wood</name> some time ago which I answered recently, also had one from <name
                type="person">Mr Price</name> a few days ago.</emotion> I can quite picture the
        changes which must have occurred in the staff of the Audit since I left. Of course you are
        over the age limit, so have not been called upon. <emotion type="negative">I expect if, and
            when, I do return safely that life in England will seem very different under the altered
            conditions. I shall be glad to get home again and only wish I could see a prospect of
            doing so, with the conclusion of this terrible war.</emotion>
        <emotion type="positive">I have had a very enjoyable time in <name type="place">India</name>
            <emotion type="negative">(apart from soldiering which I always did enjoy, although I
                think I have had sufficient now)</emotion> having made the acquaintance of awfully
            nice residents in 'Pindi, and by virtue of rank, being allowed the privilege of wearing
            mufti makes it so much more comfortable when going out of barracks than being in a tight
            uniform in the climate. I hear regularly from my wife and little one every week. Am glad
            to say they are well.</emotion></p>
    <closer> Please convey my kind regards to all those left in the office that I know. Trusting you
        are all fit and well and that we shall meet again before many more months elapse.
            <salute>With best wishes Yours most sincerely </salute>
        <signed>
            <signedname type="person">Harry Beaumont</signedname>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
