<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Harry Beaumont, 2 March 1917, Aratia, Yemen, Born: 17 October 1873, Regiment: 1/6 East
        Surrey Regiment, Regiment number: 2297, Rank: Quarter Master Sergeant, Died: 1952
        Transcript</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1917-05-02">2 March 1917</date>
            <name type="place">Aratia, Yemen</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Bertie,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p><emote type="positive">Many thanks for your long and interesting letter, which has now
            reached me, I will to it at length at a more opportune moment.</emote></p>
    <p> As you will see by above address I have left India. The regiment left the N.W. Indian
        frontier in January where <factor type="conditions">the winter had been bitterly
            cold</factor> and embarked at Karachi after a three day's train journey, <emote
            type="positive">then six day's most pleasant voyage to Aden where we landed and now join
            part of the Aden Field Force.</emote> I have been stationed with a strong detachment on
        the desert in close proximity to a Turkish force <factor type="battle">who frequently
            shelled us</factor>, but without any material damage. <emote type="neutral">The heat
            after the cold winter in India is very trying, <factor type="conditions">scorching hot
                sun, endless sand and myriads of torturing flies.</factor></emote> Life is very
        different here as compared to India. I never pictured myself riding across the Arabian
        dessert on a camel. <emote type="positive">Am pleased to say I am splendidly fit and well,
            but should be glad when the struggle is over and hope I shall be amongst those who
            return home safely.</emote></p>
    <p>Trusting you are well. Best of wishes, kind regards to the remnants of the Audit staff. </p>

    <closer>
        <salute>Yours most sincerely</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Harry Beaumont</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
