<div type="letter">
    <dateline><name type="person">Harry Beaumont</name>, <date when="1917-05-02">2 March
        1917</date>, <name type="place">Aratia, Yemen</name>, Born: 17 October 1873,
            <regiment>Regiment: 1/6 East Surrey Regiment, Regiment number: 2297</regiment>, Rank:
        Quarter Master Sergeant, Died: 1952 Transcript</dateline>
    <opener>
        <salute>Dear <name type="person">Bertie</name>,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p><emotion type="positive">Many thanks for your long and interesting letter, which has now
            reached me, I will to it at length at a more opportune moment.</emotion> As you will see
        by above address I have left <name type="place">India</name>. The regiment left the N.W.
            <name type="place">Indian</name> frontier in January where <factor type="conditions">the
            winter had been bitterly cold</factor> and embarked at <name type="place">Karachi</name>
        after a three day's train journey, <emotion type="positive">then six day's most pleasant
            voyage to <name type="place">Aden</name> where we landed and now join part of the Aden
            Field Force.</emotion> I have been stationed with a strong detachment on the desert in
        close proximity to a <name type="place">Turkish</name> force <factor type="battle">who
            frequently shelled us</factor>, but without any material damage. <emotion type="neutral"
            >The heat after the cold winter in India is very trying, <factor type="conditions"
                >scorching hot sun, <factor type="sense">endless sand</factor> and myriads of
                torturing flies.</factor></emotion> Life is very different here as compared to <name
            type="place">India</name>. I never pictured myself riding across the Arabian dessert on
        a camel. <emotion type="positive">Am pleased to say I am splendidly fit and well, but should
            be glad when the struggle is over and hope I shall be amongst those who return home
            safely.</emotion> Trusting you are well.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Best of wishes, kind regards to the remnants of the Audit staff. Yours most
            sincerely</salute>
        <signed>
            <signedname type="person">Harry Beaumont</signedname>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
