<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <!--  Mitchell Library, State Library of New South Wales Letter from <name type="person"
            >Frederick Johnson Board</name>,<date when="1917-09-07"> 7 September 1917</date> MLMSS
        9269 / Folder 6</dateline> [Page 1] <name type="place">3rd London General Hospital</name>
    <dateline>Wandsworth <date when="1917-09-07">7-9-17</date>-->
    <opener>
        <salute>My dear Miss Jamieson</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Doubtless you have heard that I <factor type="battle">got plugged</factor> some time ago and
        as a consequence have <factor type="trauma">been in Hosp for the last 9 weeks or
            more</factor>, and am now being invalided back to Australia for 6 months, so <emote
            type="positive">I may have a chance of seeing you</emote>, if I have to go to Brisbane
        on arrival. <factor type="battle"> The whole trouble rose through getting in the road of a
            Bosch high-explosive shell, which practically burst amongst 6 of us, killing one Officer
            (an Artillery chap) and wounding the other 5 of us.</factor>
        <factor type="trauma">I unfortunately stopped 4 pieces of the ironmongery (2 in the knee,
            and 2 lower down) made rather a mess of the knee for a while, but it is getting on
            pretty well now &amp; although I cant put much weight on it, I can get about fairly well
            on the patent crutches they gave me here.</factor> One Dr reckoned it would take 6
        months to get right &amp; the other doesnt think it ever be much good, but I think he's
        wrong, anyhow instead of hanging about here for 6 months, they are sending me to Sunny
        Australia for the same period &amp; to see if the leg will get better. <emote
            type="negative">I had no idea it was going to take so long and was very disappointed at
            having to give up my old Battalion which was doing so well after having practically
            selected its personnel &amp; officers and been with it for 18 months. I tell you it
            hurts to give up the old Unit, and had it over to someone else</emote> probably for
            good.</p>
    <p><emote type="positive">Do you remember Major Heron of the 42nd (used to be Capt Heron when
            they left Queensland) well he took over the 41st when I left it, and as far as I know
            still has command, with Major Sheridan as second in command. Your favourite (Capt
            French) was still going strong when I left and was in command of C Coy. He is still a
            great ladykiller(?) in fact he had the chance of 10 days leave to Paris just before I
            went there, but wouldnt take it, but he was keen on getting leave to England.. Hastings
            I guess, eh? By jove Paris was great, it is some" place, I can tell you, and dont the
            women dress, it isnt so much what they put on, but the way they wear it. It is by a long
            way the prettiest City I've seen &amp; I dont think London can hold a candle to it.
            London may be larger but I dont think it is nearly so pretty.</emote></p>
    <p>Well how is your Patriotic work getting on these days? I suppose you are as busy as ever, and
        as hard worked as ever in the interests of The Boys. Really you girls deserve the D.S.O. for
        all your splendid services. <emote type="positive">Do you know that the first suit of
            pyjamas I put on when I got into this Hosp was labelled from the Brisbane Courier Fund
            funny isnt it? It shows how far reaching are the results of various Colonial
            efforts.</emote> Well Im off to bed now, will probably be leaving for Australia in a day
        or two.Kindest regards to Mollie &amp; yourself. Hoping to see you later on U boats
        permitting.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours very sincerely</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person"> F.J. Board </name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
    <!-- source: [Transcribed by Lynne Frizell for the State Library of New South Wales]
        https://acms.sl.nsw.gov.au/_transcript/2014/D25913/a9857.html-->
</div>
