Mitchell Library, State Library of New South Wales
Letter from Frederick Johnson Board, 7 September 1917
MLMSS 9269 / Folder 6
[Page 1]
3rd London General Hospital
Wandsworth 7-9-17
My dear Miss Jamieson
Doubtless you have heard that I got “plugged" some time ago and as a consequence have been in Hosp for the last 9 weeks or more, and am now being invalided back to Australia for 6 months, so I may have a chance of seeing you, if I have to go to Brisbane on arrival. The whole trouble rose through getting in the road of a Bosch high-explosive shell, which practically burst amongst 6 of us, killing one Officer (an Artillery chap) and wounding the other 5 of us. I unfortunately “stopped" 4 pieces of the ironmongery (2 in the knee, and 2 lower down) made rather a mess of the knee for a while, but it is getting on pretty well now & although I can’t put much weight on it, I can get about fairly well on the patent crutches they gave me here.
One Dr reckoned it would take 6 months to get right & the other doesn’t think it ever be much good, but I think he’s wrong, anyhow instead of hanging about here for 6 months, they are sending me to Sunny Australia for the same period & to see if the leg will get better. I had no idea it was going to take so long and was very disappointed at having to give up my old Battalion which was doing so well after having practically selected its personnel & officers and been with it for 18 months. I tell you it hurts to give up the old Unit, and had it over to someone else
[Page 2]
probably for good. Do you remember Major Heron of the 42nd (used to be Capt Heron when they left Queensland) well he took over the 41st when I left it, and as far as I know still has command, with Major Sheridan as second in command. Your favourite (Capt French) was still “going strong" when I left and was in command of “C" Coy. He is still a great ladykiller(?) in fact he had the chance of 10 days leave to Paris just before I went there, but wouldn’t take it, but he was keen on getting leave to England.. “Hastings" I guess, eh? By jove Paris was great, it is “some" place, I can tell you, and don’t the women dress, it isn’t so much what they put on, but the way they wear it. It is by a long way the prettiest City I’ve seen & I don’t think London can hold a candle to it. London may be larger but I don’t think it is nearly so pretty.
Well how is your Patriotic work getting on these days? I suppose you are as busy as ever, and as hard worked as ever in the interests of “The Boys". Really you girls deserve the D.S.O. for all your splendid services. Do you know that the first suit of pyjamas I put on when I got into this Hosp was labelled from “the Brisbane Courier Fund" funny isn’t it? It shows how far reaching are the results of various Colonial efforts. Well I’m off to bed now, will probably be leaving for Australia in a day or two. Kindest regards to Mollie & yourself. Hoping to see you later on U boats permitting. Yours very sincerely F.J. Board
[Transcribed by Lynne Frizell for the State Library of New South Wales]
https://acms.sl.nsw.gov.au/_transcript/2014/D25913/a9857.html
