<div type="letter">
    <dateline>Mitchell Library, State Library of New South Wales Letter from <name type="person"
            >Frederick Johnson Board</name>,<date when="1917-09-07"> 7 September 1917</date> MLMSS
        9269 / Folder 6</dateline> [Page 1] <name type="place">3rd London General Hospital</name>
    <dateline>Wandsworth <date when="1917-09-07">7-9-17</date></dateline>
    <opener><salutation>My dear Miss <name type="person">Jamieson</name></salutation></opener>
    <p>Doubtless you have heard that I <factor type="battle">got plugged</factor> some time ago and
        as a consequence have <factor type="trauma">been in Hosp for the last 9 weeks or
            more</factor>, and am now being invalided back to <name type="place">Australia</name>
        for 6 months, so <emotion type="positive">I may have a chance of seeing you</emotion>, if I
        have to go to <name type="place">Brisban</name>e on arrival. <factor type="battle"> The
            whole trouble rose through getting in the road ofa Bosch high-explosive shell, which
            practically burst amongst 6 of us, killing one Officer (an Artillery chap) and wounding
            the other 5 of us.</factor>
        <factor type="trauma">I unfortunately stopped 4 pieces of the ironmongery (2 in the knee,
            and 2 lower down) made rather a mess of the knee for a while, but it <emotion
                type="positive"> is getting on pretty well now &amp; although I cant put much weight
                on it, I can get about fairly well on the patent crutches they gave me
                here.</emotion></factor> One Dr reckoned it would take 6 months to get right &amp;
        the other doesnt think it ever be much good, but I think hes wrong, anyhow instead of
        hanging about here for 6 months, they are sending me to Sunny <name type="place"
            >Australia</name> for the same period &amp; to see if the leg will get better. <emotion
            type="negative">I had no idea it was going to take so long and was very disappointed at
            having to give up my old Battalion which was doing so well after having practically
            selected its personnel &amp; officers and been with it for 18 months. I tell you it
            hurts to give up the old Unit, and had it over to someone else</emotion></p>
    <p>[Page 2] probably for good. <emotion type="positive">Do you remember <name type="person"
                >Major Heron</name> of the 42nd (used to be <name type="person">Capt Heron</name>
            when they left <name type="person">Queensland</name>) well he took over the 41st when I
            left it, and as far as I know still has command, with <name type="person">Major
                Sheridan</name> as second in command. Your favourite (<name type="person">Capt
                French</name>) was still going strong when I left and was in command of C Coy. He is
            still a great ladykiller(?) in fact he had the chance of 10 days leave to <name
                type="person">Paris</name> just before I went there, but wouldnt take it, but he was
            keen on getting leave to <name type="place">England.. Hastings</name> I guess, eh? By
            jove <name type="place">Paris</name> was great, it is some" place, I can tell you, and
            dont the women dress, it isnt so much what they put on, but the way they wear it. It is
            by a long way the prettiest City I've seen &amp; I dont think <name type="place"
                >London</name> can hold a candle to it. <name type="place">London</name> may be
            larger but I dont think it is nearly so pretty.</emotion> Well how is your Patriotic
        work getting on these days? I suppose you are as busy as ever, and as hard worked as ever in
        the interests of The Boys. Really you girls deserve the D.S.O. for all your splendid
        services. <emotion type="positive">Do you know that the first suit of pyjamas I put on when
            I got into this Hosp was labelled from the <name type="place">Brisbane</name> Courier
            Fund funny isnt it? It shows how far reaching are the results of various Colonial
            efforts.</emotion> Well Im off to bed now, will probably be leaving for <name
            type="place">Australia</name> in a day or two.Kindest regards to <name type="person"
            >Mollie</name> &amp; yourself. Hoping to see you later on U boats permitting.</p>
    <closer><salute>Yours very sincerely</salute><signed><signedname type="person"> F.J. Board
            </signedname></signed></closer>
    <!-- soruce: [Transcribed by Lynne Frizell for the State Library of New South Wales]
        https://acms.sl.nsw.gov.au/_transcript/2014/D25913/a9857.html-->
</div>
