<div type="letter">
    <dateline><name type="person">Henry Bullen</name>, <date when="1916-06-24">24 July 1916</date>,
            <name type="place">Egypt</name>. Born: <date when="1893-05-25">25 April 1893</date>,
            <regiment>Regiment: 2/10 <name type="place">Middlesex</name> regiment, Regiment number:
            2858,</regiment> Rank: Private, Died: 1942 Transcript</dateline>
    <p>An employee at the Audit office added the following note at the top of the letter: <name
            type="person">Private H. Bullen</name>, late of the Passengers dept, went through 11
        months of <name type="place">Dardanelles</name> campaign' Later moved to <name type="place"
            >Malta</name>, then to <name type="place">Egypt</name> and <name type="place"
            >Aden</name>. Now encamped near <name type="place">Mount Sinai</name>.</p>
    <opener><salute>Dear<name type="person"/>Percy</salute> ,</opener>
    <p>
        <emotion type="negative">I am sorry I have been so long replying to your letter, but I have
            had my hands rather full just lately, so hope you will not mind. As I cannot get at my
            kit bag at present I shall only be able to write you a short letter because I have
            nearly run out of paper envelopes, so I shall have to make up for it next
            time.</emotion>
    </p>
    <p>
        <emotion type="positive">Well my dear <name type="person">Percy</name> I am glad to know
            yourself and all at home are in the best of health and please convey to your father and
            mother my appreciation of their good wishes sent to me.</emotion>
    </p>
    <p>I received your previous budget, but it arrived after I sent you the field postcard, my word
        it must take you a good time to write all those sheets of foolscap, but <emotion
            type="positive">I delight in reading them, since being out here I find I cannot write an
            interesting letter.</emotion>
        <emotion type="negative">I am afraid my letters must often bore you,</emotion> I have read
        your letter carefully and noted all the news about the office and some of our friends who
        are doing their share overseas, but the chief item you mention is poor old <name
            type="person">Rippington</name>, <emotion type="negative">it is the first time I have
            heard about him, poor old chap.</emotion> I guess he was pleased to see you and I am
        sure it was an excellent idea of yours to send him some luxuries in the way of food with the
        proceeds of the money you collected for him at the office.</p>
    <p>
        <emotion type="positive">I sincerely hope our friends out in <name type="place"
                >France</name> will come out of the terrible ordeal safely, I note that <name
                type="person">Bob Court</name> and several others have gone and my brother has been
            out there some weeks now, also I have two cousins who have been out there some
            considerable time and been in the thick of the fighting, I hope the advance will mean
            the rounding up of the Huns and from the latest news received here everything seems to
            be going well at present, am looking forward to seeing the office soon.</emotion>
    </p>
    <p>
        <factor type="conditions">
            <emotion type="negative">We are not having such an easy time as one would imagine,the
                heat is still very intense and the flies very troublesome and we have anything from
                an elephant to a cockroach creeping over our blankets at night time; </emotion>
            <emotion type="positive">the chameleon is our chief pet and will crawl over one's body
                just like a tame mouse and the different colours they can change their body to suit
                the thing they settle on is wonderful.</emotion>
        </factor>
    </p>
    <p>Now I must close <name type="person">Percy</name> as you will see the paper is nearly filled
        up, so hope you will not mind this time, please remember me to all at home and all inquiring
        friends.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>With best wishes,</salute>
        <signed>
            <signedname type="person">Private H. Bullen</signedname>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
