<div type="letter">
    <dateline><name type="person">James Davies</name>, <date when="1916-06-23">23 June 1916</date>,
            <name type="place">France</name>. <regiment>Regiment: 6 City of <name type="place"
                >London</name> Rifles, Regiment number: 3343,</regiment> Rank: Lance Corporal
        Transcript</dateline>
    <opener>
        <salute>Dear <name type="person">Charles</name>,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>
        <emotion type="positive">Just a line to let you know I am getting on fine. I have been in
                <name type="place">France</name> since Good Friday morning. Well it is not so bad,
            but of course not so comfortable as the office work.</emotion>
    </p>
    <p>We had the Lord Mayor of London over to see us the other Sunday when we were resting, he made
        a little speech. How are all at the office? You might remember me to <name type="person">Mr
            Woodhams</name>, <name type="person">Mr Jones</name> and <name type="person">Mr
            Cowan</name> and the boys also the girls. I suppose <name type="person">Mr
            Redford</name> has retired by now.</p>
    <p>We have been in the trenches since the 13th and I expect we shall go out shortly. <factor
            type="conditions">Our little dugout has just been flooded out, a very heavy
            thunderstorm, but we have run it out.</factor>
        <emotion type="negative">It is rotten to see how the towns have been shelled to pieces. I
            don't suppose they will ever be rebuilt.</emotion>
        <emotion type="negative">My brother was home on leave some time ago that is the second time
            so he has not got off badly. He has been promoted to Sergeant now. He seems to be
            getting on fine</emotion>.</p>
    <p>Have you seen <name type="person">Ernie Smith</name>? How is he getting on, is he still in
        the A.P.C. (Army Pay Corps, non-fighting troops)? As I hear a lot have been transferred into
        line regiments.</p>
    <p>Well here's to the time when the war is all over and we are back in the same old place.
            <factor type="battle">The trenches where we were are only 25 to 30 yards from the Huns
            so had to keep a bit low.</factor></p>
    <p>My address is 3343 Lance Corporal J. Davies, No. 1 Platoon D Company, 6th City of <name
            type="place">London</name> Rifles, B.E.F., <name type="place">France</name>. You might
        drop me a line to let me know how you are getting on and any news,</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Kind regards</salute>
    </closer>
</div>
