<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>William Charles Davis, 15 March 1916, France. Born: 12 November 1884, Joined GWR: 12
        January 1900, Regiment: Royal Army Medical Corps, Regiment number: 31223, Rank: Lance
        Corporal; Sergeant, Retired: 1944 Transcript Sunday</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-03-15">March 15th</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear </salute>
        <name type="person">Charlie,</name>
    </opener>
    <p>How are things going with you now? I expect like the rest of us will be glad when the better
        weather sets in for there is no doubt about it, <factor type="conditions">it has been rough
            lately.</factor></p>

    <p>Since I last wrote to you<factor type="prep"> we have shifted to another part of the
            line</factor><factor type="battle">and it is a warm shop, for both sides must have all
            guns they can find and it is nothing but one long duel all day and every day but thank
            goodness it gives over a bit a night so that one can get on with their work. You see of
            a night the flashes of the guns can be seen so plainly that is why they do not fire a
            lot then.</factor>
    </p>

    <p><emote type="negative">Just on our right our people retook some trenches we had lost, oh what
            a rough time the poor devils had, <factor type="conditions">snow and mud as much as you
                like</factor> and they had to lay in it for two days and grub could not be got to
            them.</emote> I expect there have been a few more from Paddington called up by now, it
        seems if the authorities mean to have all the men they want and if they can't get them one
        way they will another, and it certainly looks as if they will be wanted for out here. <emote
            type="negative">One cannot see any signs of an early settlement.</emote> I see by the
        papers that the air raids have been busy in England again. I suppose you have not seen
        anything of them yet, has Rory Moore had any more frights? <emote type="negative"> We have
            the taubes [German aircraft] over our hospital nearly every day or night and I can tell
            you we got some starts at times.</emote><factor type="battle">The nearest we have to
            them since I have been here is just one yard from the main door, at 12.30 it blew in two
            pairs of double doors and shattered on end of the building to bits but not a great deal
            of damage to life which after all is the main thing.</factor> The arrangements we in
        work is five or six days up the line and four or five down if you are lucky. <emote
            type="negative">Of course at times these arrangements go to pot when there is an attack
            and we get a warm time and I should like to enlarge on these things but of course you
            understand I cannot.</emote></p>

    <p>Give my kind regards to all and trusting you are well. </p>
    
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours </salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Will</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
