<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>James Davies, 23 June 1916, France. Regiment: 6 City of London Rifles, Regiment number:
        3343, Rank: Lance Corporal Transcript</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-06-23">23 June 1916</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Charles,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>
        <emote type="positive">Just a line to let you know I am getting on fine. I have been in
            France since Good Friday morning. Well it is not so bad, but of course not so
            comfortable as the office work.</emote>
    </p>
    <p>We had the Lord Mayor of London over to see us the other Sunday when we were resting, he made
        a little speech. How are all at the office? You might remember me to Mr Woodhams, Mr Jones
        and Mr Cowan and the boys also the girls. I suppose Mr Redford has retired by now.</p>
    <p>We have been in the trenches since the 13th and I expect we shall go out shortly. <factor
            type="conditions">Our little dugout has just been flooded out, a very heavy
            thunderstorm, but we have run it out.</factor>
        <emote type="negative">It is rotten to see how the towns have been shelled to pieces. I
            don't suppose they will ever be rebuilt.</emote>
        <emote type="negative">My brother was home on leave some time ago that is the second time so
            he has not got off badly. He has been promoted to Sergeant now. He seems to be getting
            on fine</emote>.</p>
    <p>Have you seen Ernie Smith? How is he getting on, is he still in the A.P.C. (Army Pay Corps,
        non-fighting troops)? As I hear a lot have been transferred into line regiments.</p>
    <p>Well here's to the time when the war is all over and we are back in the same old place.
            <factor type="battle">The trenches where we were are only 25 to 30 yards from the Huns
            so had to keep a bit low.</factor></p>
    <p>My address is 3343 Lance Corporal J. Davies, No. 1 Platoon D Company, 6th City of London
        Rifles, B.E.F., France. You might drop me a line to let me know how you are getting on and
        any news,</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Kind regards</salute>
    </closer>
</div>
