Sydney Charles Douce, January 1916, Fovant Camp, Wiltshire. Born: 17
November 1882, Joined GWR: 28 November 1898, Regiment: 1/5
London Regiment; 3rd Battalion London Rifle Brigade; Royal Army Medical
Corps, Regiment number: 3701; 202204;
536657, Rank: Private, Died: 1933.
Transcript
Dear Mr. Riches
The worst has happened. The War Office has sent us down to this place
which is miles from nowhere. The camp however is made up of hundreds
of huts is according to the ‘old uns’ at the game the finest they have ever
been in, certainly everything is alright but the place is so muddy and my
time is split up. One half getting frightfully dirty and the other getting
myself clean again. However it’s all in the game and can’t be helped.
There are twenty to a hut. The beds are three long boards on two trestles
about eight or nine inches off the floor, a straw mattress and a straw
pillow, and four blankets. Not a bit what I have been used to. However I
am now quite comfortable in it and sleep like a top. Marvellous how you
think we settle down to it. Don’t you think? We rise at 6.30am. Breakfast
(porridge and bacon) at 7.30. Parade at 8.20. Drill till 10.30. Then half an
hour’s rest. Then more drill up to 12.30. Dinner at 1 o’clock (meat and
two vegetables and sweets). Parade again at 2.20. Then more drill which
brings us up to 4pm. We are then dismissed for the day. Tea at 5pm
(bread, butter and jam). After which we can do what we like until 9.15.
By this time we have to be in our huts for the final day’s roll call and at
10pm. All lights have to be out. That’s what my day consists of at
present. It may not seem much, and really it isn’t, but I am half the day
cleaning up. The grub is alright but there is not quite enough of it at
present. I think however this will be right as soon as they have made all
necessary arrangements. For the time being the Non-Commissioned
Officers seem to be a little overworked. This is the same every day, varied
on two mornings a week with a long route march in the morning. Of
course we only have half a day on Saturday and only a Church parade on
Sunday. So altogether things are not so bad. The only thing is I can’t get
away for weekends, as it would take up most of the time to travel to
London and back. I shall try however and run up to town in a few weeks’
time if possible. Kind regards to all at ‘Omega’, and everybody at 164,
W.1, including, yourself.
Yours, S.C.D.
