<div type="letter">
    <!-- <name type="person">R.C.S. Frost</name>,<date when="1916-11-23"> 23 November
                    1916</date>, <name type="place">Dartmouth, England</name>. Born: 30 January
                1888, Regiment: 8th Argyll and Sutherland Highlanders; Duke of Cornwall's Light
                Infantry, Regiment number: 1998; 300470, Rank: Private; Second Lieutenant, Died:
                1962 Transcript -->
    <opener><salute>Dear</salute>
        <name type="person">Mr Hunt</name>,</opener>
    <p>
        <emotion type="positive">Many thanks for your most welcome and interesting letter safely
            received, and I am pleased to hear of the latest news about friends at the office and
            others in different parts of the world.</emotion>
    </p>
    <p>
        <emotion type="negative">I have not had a line from <name type="person">H. Martin</name> for
            many months</emotion>, <emotion type="positive">but I hear he has had leave recently,
            and no doubt he gave you a call. I hoped to have had that pleasure before this time, but
            I expect to be seeing you one of these fine days.</emotion></p>
    <p><emotion type="neutral">I am still a patient in hospital, and although at times the life is
            monotonous in this quiet place, it is preferable to <name type="place">France</name> so
            I won't grumble.</emotion>
        <factor type="conditions">The weather has been so rough and wild of late, that a lot our
            time is spent by the fireside, and <emotion type="positive">many pleasant hours are
                passed in comparing notes with men who are patients from
            minesweepers.</emotion></factor> We have had different men from this branch of the Navy
        for several weeks, and at present five are in my ward. <factor type="trauma">Two of these
            are survivors from a minesweeper that was blown up by a <name type="place">German</name>
            mine nearly a fortnight ago, just outside <name type="place">Dartmouth Castle</name>. </factor>
        <factor type="prep">They are still clearing the sea outside here and the boats return to
            anchor in the river at night,</factor> and the pals of these men visit them this
        evening. <emotion type="positive">The officers are also very good in calling and leaving
            gifts and the wounded Tommies share in the fruits thereof!</emotion></p>
    <p>
        <emotion type="negative">I have heard from <name type="place">Scotland</name> that <factor
                type="battle">the 8th Argylls suffered heavily a short time ago in <name
                    type="place">France</name></factor>, and in the newspapers today I notice the
            names of nine officers who I knew in <name type="place">France</name>, including the
            Captain of my company who is killed. <emotion type="negative">I don't know if the 6th
                Seaforths, who are in the same brigade, were in action at the same time, but I
                shouldn't be surprised</emotion>, anyhow I hope <name type="person">[Gilbert]
                Williams </name>came through safely if he was there.</emotion> I am enclosing two
        privilege forms, and will be glad if you will get them signed and returned. <emotion
            type="positive ">I have had some nice afternoons at <name type="place">Torquay</name>
            and <name type="place">Paignton</name> and was <factor type="conditions">there during
                the rough weather a short time ago, when the Brixham trawler was wrecked and sea was
                so rough.</factor></emotion> I hope this letter will find you very well and
        undisturbed at the old job.</p>
    <closer>With kind regards to Messrs <name type="person">Taylor</name>, <name type="person"
            >Symons</name>, and <name type="person">Woodhams</name> and accept the same yourself.
            <salute>Sincerely yours</salute>, <signed>
            <signedname type="person">'Frosty'.</signedname></signed>
    </closer>
</div>
