<div type="letter">
    <!--  
        <name type="person">Richard Charles Stanley Frost</name>, <date when="1916-08-23">23 August
            1916</date>, <name type="place">Devonport, England</name>. Born: 30 January 1888,
        Regiment: 8th Argyll and Sutherland Highlanders; Duke of Cornwall's Light Infantry, Regiment
        number: 1998; 300470, Rank: Private; Second Lieutenant, Died: 1962 Transcript-->
    <opener><salute>Dear</salute>
        <name type="person">Mr Hunt</name>,</opener>
    <p>I expect you have heard at the office about me being in England <factor type="trauma"
            >suffering from gas poisoning,</factor> and as it is quite a long time since I last
        wrote to you, no doubt a few lines will be acceptable, to explain matters. <factor
            type="prep">We left the trenches at <name type="place">Vimy Ridge</name> on <date
                when="1916-07-05">July 5th</date>, and marching back about 14 miles we eventually
            reached a village named Ostreville for the purpose of having a divisional rest. The
            signallers thought an orchard would be very convenient to erect bivouacs in, so when we
            were busy carrying out this idea an old Frenchman appeared at the scene, and raised
            objections. However he agreed at last to allow us in at one end of the orchard,
            thinking, I suppose, that we would wander about his place!</factor>
        <emotion type="positive">We had an enjoyable time here for six days,</emotion> and then
            <factor type="prep">had to return to our old billets near Mount St. Eloi until the whole
            of the division had retired. We guessed by this move that our 'rest' was over, and the
            following days were spent in marching, and travelling by motor lorries and train until
            we arrived at Mericourt Station on July 21st near Albert</factor>.</p>
    <p>
        <emotion type="positive">After a delightful swim in <factor type="conditions">the river near
                the billet</factor></emotion>
        <factor type="prep">we marched off the following night, to take part in the 'big push.' We
            slept in an open field that night near Fricourt farm, and <emotion type="negative">
                <factor type="battle"> were rather rudely awakened by a few German shells landing
                    near us.</factor>
            </emotion> For five days we were lying in reserve in this district, and occupied our
            time in watching an army of men at work in the valley, making roads, railways, boring
            for water and laying down water pipes, also practicing attacks in the old trenches.
                <emotion type="positive"> It was very interesting to see the great amount of
                artillery, busy practically all day and night, and to read their messages sent by
                visual signalling [often using lights] from a ridge across the
            valley.</emotion></factor>
    </p>
    <p><factor type="prep">Our period in reserve being up, we moved to Mametz Wood to lie there in
            support for five days, before going into the trenches at High Wood.</factor>
        <factor type="battle"> On arrival at the edge of the wood at night, we were welcomed by a
            big dose of gas shells and shrapnel, which was applied steadily throughout the night by
            the German artillery. <factor type="trauma">Having to assist in putting our signalling
                gear into a hole for safety, I was prevented from using my respirator for the first
                quarter of an hour, as we could not see on account of the darkness and dust made by
                the ammunition columns rushing along the road, and it was during this time that I
                must have breathed in enough gas to put me out of action.</factor>
        </factor>
        <factor type="prep">Afterwards of course respirators were used, when we were settled in
            holes by the roadside for the night. I remained with the battalion until I was sent to
            the casualty clearing station on August 3rd and reached Rouen hospital the next day. I
            had to wait until the 9th and crossed the channel from <name type="place">Havre</name>
            to <name type="place">Southampton</name> on the <name type="place">New Zealand</name>
            ship Marama, with about 800 other patients, the day after.</factor>
        <emotion type="positive">It was a splendid boat with every convenience for carrying wounded
            men, and the sisters and orderlies were colonials.</emotion> It was last Friday week
        when I arrived here, and must say <emotion type="positive">it is very comfortable and quiet.
            I had to remain in bed until last Saturday, but of course I cannot do any route marching
            yet! So I have to take life quietly, which is no hardship I can assure you after <name
                type="place">France</name>.</emotion> I am on an ordinary diet, and taking
        medicine.</p>
    <p>I hear you have <name type="person">Mr Symons</name> back again, is that so? And is he back
        in the same old spot?<emotion type="neutral"> I hope he is pretty fit, although I suppose
            there must be something wrong with him, to be back again.</emotion> I suppose things are
        as quiet as usual with you. Have you had your holidays yet? This is about your time I
        believe. I shall be glad of a few lines when you have time, to hear the latest about the
        office.</p>
    <closer>I hope you are keeping fit, also <name type="person">Mr J.B. Taylor</name> and <name
            type="person">Mr Woodhams</name> and with kind regards to you all. <salute>Yours
            sincerely</salute>, <signed>
            <signedname type="person">Frosty.</signedname>
        </signed>
    </closer>
    <postscript>P.S. It is a treat to write a letter without the censor's shadow over one!</postscript>
</div>
