<text>
    <body>
        <div type="letter">
            <meta><name type="person">R.C.S. Frost</name>,<date when="1916-11-23"> 23 November
                    1916</date>, <name type="place">Dartmouth, England</name>. Born: 30 January
                1888, Regiment: 8th Argyll and Sutherland Highlanders; Duke of Cornwall's Light
                Infantry, Regiment number: 1998; 300470, Rank: Private; Second Lieutenant, Died:
                1962 Transcript</meta>
            <opener><salute>Dear</salute>
                <name type="person">Mr Hunt</name>,</opener>
            <p>Many thanks for your most welcome and interesting letter safely received, and I am
                pleased to hear of the latest news about friends at the office and others in
                different parts of the world.</p>
            <p>I have not had a line from H. Martin for many months, but I hear he has had leave
                recently, and no doubt he gave you a call. I hoped to have had that pleasure before
                this time, but I expect to be seeing you one of these fine days.</p>
            <p>I am still a patient in hospital, and although at times the life is monotonous in
                this quiet place, it is preferable to France so I won't grumble. The weather has
                been so rough and wild of late, that a lot our time is spent by the fireside, and
                many pleasant hours are passed in comparing notes with men who are patients from
                minesweepers. We have had different men from this branch of the Navy for several
                weeks, and at present five are in my ward. Two of these are survivors from a
                minesweeper that was blown up by a German mine nearly a fortnight ago, just outside
                Dartmouth Castle. They are still clearing the sea outside here and the boats return
                to anchor in the river at night, and the pals of these men visit them this evening.
                The officers are also very good in calling and leaving gifts and the wounded Tommies
                share in the fruits thereof!</p>
            <p>I have heard from Scotland that the 8th Argylls suffered heavily a short time ago in
                France, and in the newspapers today I notice the names of nine officers who I knew
                in France, including the Captain of my company who is killed. I don't know if the
                6th Seaforths, who are in the same brigade, were in action at the same time, but I
                shouldn't be surprised, anyhow I hope [Gilbert] Williams came through safely if he
                was there. I am enclosing two privilege forms, and will be glad if you will get them
                signed and returned. I have had some nice afternoons at Torquay and Paignton and was
                there during the rough weather a short time ago, when the Brixham trawler was
                wrecked and sea was so rough. I hope this letter will find you very well and
                undisturbed at the old job.</p>
            <closer>With kind regards to Messrs Taylor, Symons, and Woodhams and accept the same
                yourself. <salute>Sincerely yours</salute>, <signed>
                    <name type="person">'Frosty'.</name></signed>
            </closer>
        </div>
    </body>
</text>
