<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>R.C.S. Frost,23 November 1916, Dartmouth, England. Born: 30 January 1888, Regiment: 8th
        Argyll and Sutherland Highlanders; Duke of Cornwall's Light Infantry, Regiment number: 1998;
        300470, Rank: Private; Second Lieutenant, Died: 1962 Transcript</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-11-23"> 23 November 1916</date>
            <name type="place">Dartmouth, England</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear</salute>
        <name type="person">Mr Hunt,</name>
    </opener>
    <p>
        <emote type="positive">Many thanks for your most welcome and interesting letter safely
            received, and I am pleased to hear of the latest news about friends at the office and
            others in different parts of the world.</emote>
    </p>
    <p>
        <emote type="negative">I have not had a line from H. Martin for many months</emote>, <emote
            type="positive">but I hear he has had leave recently, and no doubt he gave you a call. I
            hoped to have had that pleasure before this time, but I expect to be seeing you one of
            these fine days.</emote></p>
    <p><emote type="neutral">I am still a patient in hospital, and although at times the life is
            monotonous in this quiet place, it is preferable to France so I won't grumble.</emote>
        <factor type="conditions">The weather has been so rough and wild of late, that a lot our
            time is spent by the fireside,</factor> and <emote type="positive">many pleasant hours
            are passed in comparing notes with men who are patients from minesweepers.</emote></p>

    <p>We have had different men from this branch of the Navy for several weeks, and at present five
        are in my ward. <factor type="trauma">Two of these are survivors from a minesweeper that was
            blown up by a German mine nearly a fortnight ago, just outside Dartmouth Castle. </factor>
        <factor type="prep">They are still clearing the sea outside here and the boats return to
            anchor in the river at night,</factor> and the pals of these men visit them this
        evening. <emote type="positive">The officers are also very good in calling and leaving gifts
            and the wounded Tommies share in the fruits thereof!</emote></p>
    <p>
        <emote type="negative">I have heard from Scotland that <factor type="battle">the 8th Argylls
                suffered heavily a short time ago in France</factor>, and in the newspapers today I
            notice the names of nine officers who I knew in France, including the Captain of my
            company who is killed. I don't know if the 6th Seaforths, who are in the same brigade,
            were in action at the same time, but I shouldn't be surprised, anyhow I hope [Gilbert]
            Williams came through safely if he was there.</emote></p>
    
    <p>I am enclosing two privilege forms, and will be glad if you will get them signed and
        returned. <emote type="positive ">I have had some nice afternoons at Torquay and Paignton
            and was <factor type="conditions">there during the rough weather a short time ago, when
                the Brixham trawler was wrecked and sea was so rough.</factor></emote> I hope this
        letter will find you very well and undisturbed at the old job. With kind regards to Messrs
        Taylor, Symons, and Woodhams and accept the same yourself.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">'Frosty'.</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
