<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info> This transcript is from a letter by Private Leonard Hart to his parents on 19 October
        1917. Hart describes in detail the terrible events of 12 October 1917 when New Zealand
        troops were asked to take the Bellvue Spur, near Passchendaele. Historian Jock Phillip
        writes, 'this distressing, but accurate, description of the battle ... is a remarkable piece
        of writing, particularly given Hart's lack of formal education.' The transcript is from Jock
        Phillips and Nicholas Boyack (eds), The great adventure, New Zealand soldiers describe the
        First World War, Allen and Unwin, Wellington, 1998 </info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1917-10-19">Oct 19, 1917</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Mother, Father and Connie,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>In a postcard which I sent you about a fortnight ago, I mentioned that we were on the eve of
        a great event, and that I had no time to write you a long letter. <emote type="positive"
            >Well that great event is over now, and by some strange act of fortune I have once again
            come through without a scratch</emote>.</p>
    <p>
        <factor type="battle">The great event mentioned consisted of a desperate attack by our
            Division against a ridge, strongly fortified and strongly held by the Germans, but the
            name of which I had better not mention.</factor>
        <emote type="negative">For the first time in our brief history as an army the New Zealanders
            failed in their objective with the most appalling slaughter I have ever seen.</emote> My
        Company went into action 180 strong and we came out thirty-two strong. <emote type="neutral"
            >Still, we have nothing to be ashamed of as our commander afterwards told us that no
            troops in the world could possibly have taken the position</emote>, <emote
            type="negative">but this is small comfort when one remembers the hundreds of lives that
            have been lost and nothing gained.</emote>I will give you an account of the battle as
        near as I can without meaning any names or exasperating the censor (should he happen to open
        this) too much.</p>
    <p>
        <factor type="battle">On a certain Wednesday evening our Brigade received orders to proceed
            to the firing line and relieve a Brigade of Tommies who had two nights previously
            advanced their positions a distance of two thousand yards and had held the captured
            ground against several counter attacks by the Huns.</factor>
        <emote type="negative">These Tommies had, however, failed to take their last objective and
            we knew before we left that we were going to be put over the top to try and take
            it.</emote> At dusk we started off from <factor type="conditions">the town where we had
            been billeted for a few days, in full fighting order, to proceed to the front
            line.</factor> Our track led over five miles of newly conquered ground without lines of
        communication, roads, or anything but shell holes half full of water. The weather had for
        some days been wet and cold and the mud was in places up to the knees. <emote
            type="negative">We struggled on through this sea of mud for some hours, and everyone was
            feeling pretty well done.</emote> It was quite common for a man to get stuck in the mud
        and have to get three or four to drag him out. <emote type="negative">You can have no idea
            of the utter desolation caused by modern shell fire.</emote> The ground we were
        traversing had all been deluged with our shells before being taken from the Germans, <factor
            type="conditions">and for those five miles leading to our front line trench there was
            nothing but utter desolation, not a blade of grass, or tree, here and there a heap of
            bricks marking where a village or farmhouse had once stood, numerous ‘tanks’ stuck in
            the mud, and for the rest, just one shell hole touching another.</factor>
    </p>
    <p>
        <factor type="conditions">The torn up condition of the ground made the mud ten times worse
            than it would otherwise have been. The only structures which had stood the bombardment
            in any way at all were the German machine gun emplacements.</factor>
        <emote type="positive">These emplacements are marvellous structures made of concrete with
            walls often ten feet thick and the concrete reinforced throughout with railway irons and
            steel bands and bars. There is room inside them for a large number of men but of course
            they vary in size.</emote> Many of these emplacements had been shattered to pieces in
        spite of their strength but others had withstood the bombardment. The ground was strewn with
        the corpses of numerous Huns and Tommies. Dead horse and mules lay everywhere, yet no
        attempt had been made to bury any of them. Well, we at length arrived at our destination –
        the front line and relieved the worn out Tommies. <emote type="negative"> They had not
            attempted to dig trenches but had simply held the line by occupying a long line of shell
            holes, two or three men to each hole.</emote><factor type="trauma"> Many of them seemed
            too worn out to walk properly and I don’t know how some of them must have got on during
            their long tramp through the mud back to billets.</factor>
    </p>
    <p><factor type="prep">Each of us had a shovel with him, so we set to work to make some kind of
            trenches.</factor> We were at this point about half way up one slope of the ridge which
        in the course of fortyeight hours we were to try and take. <emote type="positive">The mud
            was not so bad here owing to the water being able to run away into a swamp at the foot
            of the ridge.</emote>
        <factor type="prep">Anyway by daybreak we had dug ourselves in sufficiently and, although
            wet and covered in mud from head to foot, we felt fit for a feed of bread and bully
            beef, for breakfast. We stayed in our new trenches all that day and the day following
            during which it rained off and on, and Fritz kept things lively with his
            artillery.</factor>
        <factor type="battle">At 3 o’clock on the third morning we received orders to attack the
            ridge at half past five, which was just before daylight. We were accordingly arranged in
            three successive waves or lines; each wave about fifty yards ahead of the
            other.</factor>
        <factor type="conditions"> There was a certain amount of difficulty in this operation as it
            was pitch dark and raining heavily.</factor> When all was ready we were told to lay down
        and wait the order to charge. <emote type="negative">My Company was in the first wave of the
            attack which partly accounted for our heavy casualties.</emote> Our artillery barrage
        (curtain of fire) was to open out at twenty past five and play on the German positions on
        top of the ridge 150 yards ahead of us. It was to move forward fifty yards in every four
        minutes – that is to say we were to advance as our barrage advanced and keep 100 to 150
        yards behind it.</p>
    <p>
        <factor type="battle">At twenty past five to the second, and with a roar that shook the
            ground, some three thousand of our guns opened out on the five mile sector of the
            advance. (The whole advance was on a five mile front and our Brigade occupied about a
            thousand yards of this front forming the centre of the advance. Our Rifle Brigade was on
            our left and a Tommy Division on the left of them again.</factor> An Australian Division
        was on our right and another Tommy Division on the right of them again.) Through some
        blunder our artillery barrage opened up about two hundred yards short of the specified range
        and thus opened right in the midst of us. <emote type="negative"> It was a truly awful time
            – our own men getting cut to pieces in dozens by our own guns. Immediate disorganisation
            followed.</emote>
        <factor type="battle">I heard an officer shout an order to the men to retire a short
            distance and wait for our barrage to lift. Some, who heard the order, did so. Others,
            not knowing what to do under the circumstances, stayed where they were, while others
            advanced towards the German positions, only to be mown down by his deadly rifle and
            machine gun fire.</factor>
    </p>
    <p>
        <factor type="battle">At length our barrage lifted and we all once more formed up and made a
            rush for the ridge.</factor>
        <emote type="negative"> What was our dismay upon reaching almost to the top of the ridge to
            find a long line of practically undamaged German concrete machine gun emplacements with
            barbed wire entanglements in front of them fully fifty yards deep.</emote> The wire had
        been cut in a few places by our artillery but only sufficient to allow a few men through it
        at a time. <emote type="negative"> Even then what was left of us made an attempt to get
            through the wire and a few actually penetrated as far as his emplacements only to be
            shot down as fast as they appeared. Dozens got hung up in the wire and shot down before
            their surviving comrades’ eyes. It was now broad daylight and what was left of us
            realised that the day was lost.</emote> We accordingly lay down in shell holes or any
        cover we could get and waited. Any man who showed his head was immediately shot. <emote
            type="neutral">They were maravellous shots those Huns.</emote> We had lost nearly eighty
        per cent of our strength and gained about 300 yards of ground in the attempt. This 300 yards
        was useless to us for the Germans still held and dominated the ridge. We hung on all that
        day and night. There was no one to give us orders, all our officers of the Battalion having
        been killed or wounded with the exception of three, and these were all Second Lieutenants
        who could not give a definite order about the position without authority. All my Company
        officers were killed outright one of them the son of the Reverend Ryburn of Invercargill,
        was shot dead beside me. </p>
    <p>The second day after <emote type="negative">this tragic business</emote>, we were surprised
        to see about half a dozen Huns suddenly appear waving a white flag. They proved to be red
        cross men and the flag was a sign that they were asking for a truce to take in their wounded
        and bury their dead. It was granted and not a shot was fired on either side during the whole
        of that afternoon. <emote type="positive">It was a humane and gallant act and one worthy of
            such gallant defenders as those particular Huns certainly were.</emote> Our stretcher
        bearers were able to go and take all our wounded from the barbed wire, a thing that would
        have been impossible otherwise. <factor type="prep">Numbers of us who at ordinary times had
            nothing to do with stretcher bearing were put on and we had all the wounded carried out
            before nightfall. We had no time to bury many of our dead but the wounded should be the
            only consideration at times like that.</factor> I went out and buried poor Ryburn. He
        came with the Main Body, but had not been in France long. <emote type="neutral">The
            proportion of killed to wounded was exceptionally high compared to other battles, owing
            to the perfect marksmanship of the German machine gunners and snipers.</emote>
        <emote type="negative">My Company has come out with no officers, only one Sergeant out of
            seven, one Corporal and thirty men. Even then we are not the worst off.</emote></p>
    <p>
        <factor type="prep">T he third night after the advance we were relieved and taken back about
            three miles behind the line. Here we acted as a reserve to the Battalion which had taken
            over our sector for two days, and we were finally taken right out to billets well behind
            the line where we are now recuperating.</factor> The night we came out here I received a
        parcel from you. The note inside was dated 10/7/17, and I can tell you that I felt hungry
        enough to eat note and all. I received another parcel from you about three days before we
        shifted to this front which would be about three weeks ago. They were appreciated about as
        well as it is possible to appreciate anything, I can assure you. Your letters of Mamma’s
        25/7/17, Connie’s of same date and Dad’s of 7/7/17 arrived about a week before the affair of
        the ridge. <factor type="trauma">A number of our chaps who came through have since been sent
            to hospital chiefly with trench feet due to standing in cold mud for long hours. I have
            a touch of them myself but they are not bad enough to be sent away with.</factor> I have
        just decided to have this letter posted by someone going on leave to England, so I will tell
        you a few more facts which it would not have been advisable to mention otherwise.......</p>
    <p>Fighting of a very successful nature had been going on around Ypres for some months previous
        to our late set back at the ridge where the British are now held up. I hear that another
        attempt is to be made to take it, but it will not be with our Division. The name of this
        famous ridge is Passchendaele Ridge, and it has defied two attempts to take it already – viz
        the one attempted by the Tommies whom we relieved and our own......</p>
    <p>The results of our stunt you now know so no more need be said about it except that we did as
        well or even better that some of the Divisions on our right and left. None of them took
        their objectives and I know for a fact that our Third Brigade’s losses and those of the
        Australians were every bit as heavy as ours. The Second Brigade has at least the
        satisfaction of knowing that they held a few hundred yards of ground they took, <emote
            type="neutral"> and our commander has since told us that no troops in the world could
            possibly have taken the ridge under similar circumstances. </emote>
        <emote type="negative"> Some ‘terrible blunder’ has been made. Someone is responsible for
            that barbed wire not having been broken up by our artillery. Someone is responsible for
            the opening of our barrage in the midst of us instead of 150 yards ahead of us. Someone
            else is responsible for those machine gun emplacements being left practically intact,
            but the papers will all report another glorious success, and no one except those who
            actually took part in it will know any different.</emote></p>
    <p>In conclusion I will relate to you another little incident or two which never reaches the
        press, or if it does it is ‘censored’ in order to deceive the public. This almost
        unbelievable but perfectly true incident is as follows. During the night after we had
        relieved the Tommies prior to our attack on the ridge we were surprised to hear agonised
        cries of ’stretcher bearer’, ‘help’, ‘For God’s sake come here’ etc, coming from all sides
        of us. When daylight came some of us, myself included, crawled out to some adjacent shell
        holes from where the cries were coming and were astonished to find about <factor
            type="trauma"> half a dozen Tommies, badly wounded, some insane, others almost dead with
            starvation and exposure, lying stuck in the mud and too weak to move. We asked one man
            who seemed a little better than the rest what was the meaning of it and he said that if
            we cared to crawl about the shell holes all round about him we would find dozens more in
            similar plight.</factor></p>
    <p>We were dumbfounded, but the awful truth remained. <emote type="negative">These chaps,
            wounded in the defence of their country, had been callously left to die the most awful
            of deaths in <factor type="conditions">the half frozen mud while tens of thousands of
                able bodied men were camped within five miles of them behind the lines.</factor>
        </emote> All these Tommies (they were mostly men of the York and Lancaster Regiment) had
        been wounded during their unsuccessful attack on the ridge which we afterwards tried to take
        and at the time when we came upon them they must have been <factor type="conditions">lying
            where they fell in the mud and rain for four days and nights.</factor> Those that were
        still alive had subsisted on the rations and water that they had carried with them or else
        had taken it from dead comrades beside them. <emote type="negative">I have seen some pretty
            rotten sights during the two and half years of active service, but I must say that this
            fairly sickened me.</emote> We crawled back to our trenches and inside of an hour all
        our stretcher bearers were working like the heroes that they were, and in full view of the
        enemy who, to his credit, did not fire on them. <emote type="negative">They worked all day
            carrying out those Tommies of whom I am afraid some will be mad men for the rest of
            their lives even if they do recover from their wounds and exposure</emote>.</p>
    <p>Carrying wounded over such country often knee deep in mud is the most trying work imaginable,
        and I do not say for a moment that the exhausted Tommies (the survivors of the first attack
        on Passchendale Ridge) whom we relieved should have tried to carry them out for I do not
        believe that any of them were physically capable of doing it, but I do say that it was part
        of their officers’ duty to send back to the rear of the lines and have fresh men brought up
        to carry out the wounded that they themselves could not carry. <emote type="negative">
            Perhaps they did send back for help, but still the fact remains that nothing was done
            until our chaps came up, and whoever is responsible for the unnecessary sacrifice of
            those lives deserves to be shot more than any Hun ever did.</emote></p>
    <p>If they had asked for an armistice to carry out their wounded I do not doubt that it would
        have been granted for the Huns had plenty of wounded to attend to as well as the Tommies.
            <emote type="negative">I suppose our armchair leaders call this British stubbornness. If
            this represents British stubbornness then it is time we called it by a new name. I would
            suggest callous brutality as a substitute.</emote> Apparently this is not an isolated
        instance of its kind. <emote type="negative">While we were in reserve for two days to the
            Brigade which finally took over from us I was having a look around some old German
            dugouts and in one of them I came upon about fifty dead Tommies all lying spread out
            over the floor as though they had been thrown in there hastily. They had evidently been
            dead some months. I asked an artillery Sergeant Major standing near by how they all came
            to be in there and he told me that they had been put in there (while wounded) during the
            advance last July, and had been forgotten. If this were true then it is even worse than
            the case just mentioned, for these dugouts must have been within a mile of our main
            dressing stations at the time when the advance took place, and the distance to carry
            them was thus five times less than in the other case. </emote>
    </p>
    <p>
        <emote type="negative"> After reading this do not believe our lying press, who tell you that
            all the brutality of this war is on the Huns’ side. The Hun is no angel, we all know,
            and the granting of an armistice such as that which we had is a rare occurrence. The
            particular Regiments who were holding the ridge at the time our attack are known as
            ‘Jaegers’. Probably the Prussians or most of the other Hun Regiments do not ask for
            armistices, but for all the terrific casualties those Jaegers inflicted on us, we
            survivors of Passchendaele Ridge must all admit that they played the game on that
            occasion at any rate......</emote>
    </p>
    <closer>
        <salute>I remain Your affectionate son</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Len</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
