<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>James Walter Hyam, 15 April 1918, Roorkee, India. Born: 24 July 1891, Regiment: 11
        Hussars, C. Squadron; Royal Field Artillery; Royal Garrison Artillery, Regiment number:
        223725; 184963, Rank: Gunner, Died: 1951 When James Hyam, also nick-named Fatty, wrote from
        India he used these three postcards which showed different scenes from Alexandria in Egypt
        where he had 'a grand time' en-route to India. Transcript</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1918-04-15">April 15th</date>
            <name type="place">Roorkee, India</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>My Dear</salute>
        <name type="person">Bertie,</name>
    </opener>
    <p>Have arrived in India for the purpose of relieving some A1 (military fitness category meaning
        capable of active service overseas) men here who have been here for a long period. It's not
        a bad show here just above Delhi but <factor type="conditions">so d____d hot: risen to 106
            degrees in the shade and we have more hot weather just coming.</factor> Our parades are
        as follows 6.30-7.45 and 9 to 10 and finish for day. <emote type="positive">There is an
            abundance of sport and grub here. Fancy getting eggs laid too. A supper of say new
            mutton chop, potatoes, peas, broccoli and tea 4d.</emote>
    </p>
    <p>The things that are expensive are goods from England especially English soap, sauces, writing
        paper and of course we are unable to get English made fags. We had a grand journey from
        England; route was Southampton to Cherbourg then to Italy. In Italy we went to Alexandria,
        stayed there three days <emote type="positive">had a grand time, streets of red lamps etc.
            and lovely shops. No two houses in main stretch are alike.</emote> Then from Alexandria
        we come to Port Suez by train then on P. and O. Liner Kaiser I. Hind to Bombay had two days
        there and that's a grand place too, lovely wide streets and grand buildings. They have a sea
        front very much like Hastings and all the big boys have their after dinner drive there and
        form a queue by shore. Some stuff there too. Lots of Europeans knocking about too. <emote
            type="positive"> Had a game of footer for the Railway Operatives depot last night, 6pm,
            with Kingls Own and won. But it was so ruddy warm and I felt like a wash out at finish.
        </emote></p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Kind regards to all. Give Bill Butler my address and ask him to drop a
            line.</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">J.W. Hyam, Fatty.</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
    <postscript>How are the tours going is Frosty still serving?</postscript>
</div>
