<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info> Source:National Library of New Zealande Collection:MS-Papers-0421: Inglis, Lindsay
        Merritt (Major General), 1894-1966 : Papers Author: Inglis, Lindsay Merritt (Major General)
        Strand Place Hotel, Strand, London, W.C.2.</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1918-08-14">14-8-18</date>
            <name type="place">Strand Place Hotel, Strand, London</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Old Girl,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Here goes for another small note to swell your budget at the post and to relate events.<emote
            type="positive">Thus far I have been as lazy as I can be. Yesterday and the day before I
            have been buzzing around during the day doing a fair amount of necessary shopping, and
            temp(?) now almost fined up for my immediate wants - except for what the tailor is
            making.</emote> Will cease that sort of uncertainty till just before I go back when I
        shall plunge in and buy any bulky stuff I want to take back. And talking of shopping -<emote
            type="negative">I can't make up my mind what to get for you. You have asked of course
            for something that would do for our home - but so far I haven't got any further ahead
            with the choosing.</emote><emote type="positive">Then in one of your last letters you
            talked of some blouse materials you coveted, and that gave me inspiration</emote>- if I
        could only land somebody to choose them. I've another idea too. I shall try it on. Don't be
        curious, mum, and you won't be told no lies.</p>
    <p><emote type="positive">Yesterday afternoon I met(redacted)'s office of the Otago Regiment,
            and we had several games of five and a swim at the Royal Automobile Club. We also spent
            the evening together smoking and yarning. The day before I had dinner with Charley
            Foradick and later on we went round to the Waldorf Hotel to look up Geddis who was
            staying there only another day or two of leave to run. We found him just turning in, so
            dug him out of bunk and held a party in his room till a very later hour, when we left
            him in peace and went our several ways to beds</emote>. Geddis -- commonly known to us
        as "Little Willie" has a great attraction at a place called Livydon(?) not very far from
        London - a pretty girl who has absorbed most of his attention during his leaves. I half
        suspected to find him getting married this time. Forsdick and I offered our assistance and
        promised to make fitting speeches if he would arrange the ceremony; but he said the time was
        not yet ripe and offered to make it a double event with me.</p>
    <p><emote type="neutral">Did I ever tell you, dear, that the word of our engagement was bruited
            around the N.Z.E.F in France sometime about March last?</emote>Well there is a paper of
        N.Z. news called the "New Zealander" printed by some benevolent person and issued free to us
        periodically, and there it was - copied of course from N.Z. papers. <emote type="positive">I
            have been collecting congratulations from then on.</emote>Dearest old chap, things are
        not pouring out of my throat onto the paper with the greatest of ease. Same old
            complaint.<emote type="negative">I feel that I am getting very stale and as dull as
            dishwater, and since Forsdick wants to take me to meet some of the friends he has made
            in England I shall be only too pleased to take the opportunity and try to combat the
            tendency.</emote> I wouldn't be surprised if that is what I need. A man deprived of
        feminine society grows rough edges after a time too - I'm sure I don't know what you'll find
        me like when I get back to you, old chap. You'd better collect some files and sandpaper for
        the process of smoothing me off again! Darling girl,keep your pecker up and smile. <emote
            type="negative">I think I miss you more on leave than at any other time.</emote></p>
    <p>
        <emote type="negative">It feels so much like burning daylight to be without you in a place
            like this. Quite different from being with the company where I wouldn't have you come
            for the world - much as I long for you.</emote> Do you see, old chap? Stop me, old lady
        - I"m getting to be a confirmed growler. <emote type="positive">I am fit and well,
            dear.</emote>
        <emote type="negative">Always very much love and longing for you. I've almost forgotten what
            it feels like to have you in my arms.</emote>
        <emote type="positive">But someday I'm going to remind both of us just exactly what it's
            like. Let's have a big wish together for the chance to come soon.</emote> In the
        meantime, sweetheart, there is always "this". All my love for your dear old self.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Your</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Lindsay.</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
