<div type="letter">
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <name type="person">Harold Kerr</name>
            <date when="1915-08-06">August 6, 1915</date>
        </dateline>
    </opener>
    <p><emotion type="positive">Things have been very quiet hear the last week, <factor
                type="battle">with the exception of a little shell fire both from the <name
                    type="place">Turks</name> and our own guns.</factor></emotion>
        <factor type="battle">The night before last our fellows made a charge on our right flank and
            took two line of trenches. first of all they blew up the <name type="place">Turks</name>
            trenches and then charged before the dust had time to settle. They cut off the <name
                type="place">Turks</name> in one trench and the others run for their lives leaving
            their rifles behind. They are afraid to face the cold steel.</factor>
        <emotion type="neutral">We expect to have some excitement in a few days, things are too
            quiet to last, but I suppose you will read about it in the <name type="place"
                >Australian</name> papers.</emotion> Well <name type="person">Aub</name> I must say
        good-bye.</p>
    <closer>Remember me to <name type="person">Jim</name>. <salute>From your loving brother</salute>
        <signed>
            <signedname type="person">Harold</signedname>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
