<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Mitchell Library, State Library of New South Wales George Washington Thomas Lambert
        letter, 7 August 1919 MLMSS 97/4/Item 2 [Transcribers note: The letter dated 7 August 1919
        is written to his wife from Marseilles when George Lambert is on his way back to London from
        Egypt. The pages after the letter appear to be part of his diary written when he was at
        Moascar, Egypt towards the end of his time in that country.] [Page 1] Lambert Family Papers
        George Washington Thomas Lambert Papers re War Service, 1915-1919 Loose sheets from War
        Diary, 1919 (ML MSS.97/4 Item 1) [Page 2] Rest Camp Marseilles</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1919-08-07">August 7th</date>
            <name type="place">unknown</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Mick</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>After a very <emote type="positive">delightful &amp; peaceful</emote> voyage across the
        Meditteranean the long &amp; rugged arms of Marseilles Harbour enclose us safely; and with
        the French green trees &amp; <factor type="conditions">mild sunshine the blue water &amp;
            cooling breezes</factor> one may perhaps for an hour forget. Forget now for an hour the
        awful country we have left, I trust for ever as far as Im concerned. <emote type="positive"
            >My health state is good and improving</emote>. This break is annoying but we may resume
        our journey tomorrow. I will let you know by wire my progress towards London. The worst is
        over &amp; I feel I shall arrive in good trim possibly 4 to 5 days after you receive
        this.</p>
    <p>The mess room is demobilizing itself. Once a smart hut capable of dining about 30 officers in
        style. Brick walls, timber roof, Egyptian colours on the walls. Roof still there, walls
        demobilizing colours blending artistically having lost most of their suddeness on the
        Tussour shirts of the tired Heads. (Tired exhausted Heads Staff Officers.) <factor
            type="conditions">Thousands of flies</factor>, that likeThethe Intelligent. Natives
        realize that the screens are faulty and hop in for Their cut while the going is good"
        (Australian for Seize your opportunity"). The comparison between parasites and intelligent
        Natives must not be laboured as this is even now a military letter and the Censor may even
        at this stage be on the spot, namely doing his duty under terrific odds. Outside this bit of
        shade (111 Fahrenheit) there is a blaze of almost colourless light and it takes, even for an
        experienced savage like myself, a few seconds to locate the differences between sand, tents
        and sky. In this blaze work still goes on, army work which is like every other kind of work,
        I meeself yesterday sat out in the blaze and did an accurate drawing of a cacolet (Cacolet
        two stretchers attached to camel for field ambulance work). [See image for drawing.] The
        work goes on but with that greatest of all physical efforts, the effort to do ones duty
        during the last hours of a long contract.</p>
    <p>There have been backslidings and senseless noise and a scrap here and there but I am dealing
        now with myself and the men who appeal to me. The others can be dealt with by the
        A.P.M.inand possibly by some damned journalist who sings the song of the Bolschevick. I am
        writing because I have no duties for two or three hours, merely finishing my diary, packing
        my stuff or rather assisting my offsider to do it. I shall finish I hope a sketch of Ismalia
        this evening. But to our muttons Take my man. <factor type="prep">He is carefully
            rearranging &amp; packing pictures, materials, clothes</factor> &amp;c. renovating cases
        with nails he has to find patiently, thoroughly. A group of men the last of the A.P.Ms
        outfit ride past in the same old Australian manner taking their horses down to water.
        Perhaps tomorrow their horses will be handed in but today they will be watered, fed,
        groomed, and told with the harsh voice which conceals emotion that they are Bastards. Just
        alongside my hut Signals (Telegraph &amp; Telephone Office) keeps up its monotonous Moascar,
        Moascar, Yes Sir or Hello! How she go" as the case requires. Sometimes the call rings or
        burrs and the worn out operator fails to hear it at once, his offsider or the man who is
        about to relieve him wakes up and giving a rub to his face with a towel to removegetsome of
        the sweat &amp; sleepinessfrom his face</p>
    <p>walks over to the receiver &amp; takes the call after which he curses his mate who wakes up
        &amp; continues Moascar"! Some swell writer or some swollen writer used to say, The Time (or
        Times, the day, or the period) was big with portent. Anticipation of great things to come is
        of course the sheet anchor of the hopeful child and disappointed adult. We that is Us" are
        in or near to the land where conception gained the word Divine after many million years of
        primitive literary effort, and the most of us are still willing to create &amp; build in our
        work and all of us are capable of doing our humble part in the productive process of
        bringing more men &amp; women into the world but to have to clean up, something my dear wife
        that you understand, is Hell and must be done; and I want to express not so much wonder at
        myself because I have many interests but at the war" generally and to say finally that this
        day is big. Incident every minute. A sentry standing to attention, merely as a matter of
        habit. This page was interrupted by the sound of a horse grunting and a man cursing and I
        ran into the blaze to see what is possibly the last buck jumper trying to get his man off
        just as if the war was beginning.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>For Finish Ref. Personal paragraph to Wife.</salute>
       <name type = "person"> G.W.L.</name>
    </closer>
</div>
