<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <opener>
        <name type="person">William Perrin Mansbridge</name>
        <dateline>
            <date when="17 March 1916"/>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Gerald,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>No doubt, perhaps you had thought I had forgotten old friends at Paddington, but such is not
        the case. We so not have much spare time for letter writing now. To tell you of all our
        adventures since we left England would take too long here to relate but I will save for when
        I come home. Perhaps you have heard, we were only at Farnborough four days, before we were
        sent over there. By God, old chap we did have a time of it, the first fortnight. Living on
        bully beef and biscuits, <factor type="prep">travelling day and night and sleeping
            anywhere</factor> and doing long tramps with full kit on nearly done us in as we had no
        training. We managed to stick it through, but I thought poor Percy Smith would have to give
        in as he was very queer with toothache. The first six weeks we moved about from place to
        place <factor type="prep">doing all sorts of fatigue work</factor>, bar our own. Lambert,
        Smith, Collins and myself are now settled down in H the place where Mr Lakers son was so
        long at. Collins and Lambert have been fortunate enough to get temporary clerical work
        during the last months. </p>
    <p>I was promised one when on the 17th of last month <emote type="negative">I was <trauma>wounded</trauma> by a
                <factor type="battle">bomb</factor></emote> from a taube which landed clean through
        our billet at 12 oclock at night, when we were all sound asleep. I caught it in the thigh,
        but luckily it was only a flesh wound, but <emote type="negative">I had some <factor
                type="trauma">awful bruises</factor> from the debris</emote> which fell on it. I
        have been in hospital ever since at the base, but I am pleased to say <emote type="positive"
            >I am now nearly well again</emote> and in a convalescent camp three miles from there,
        overlooking the sea. We are not allowed to put our address at the heading of a letter so I
        will put it here:</p>
    <p> 2AM /W.P. Mansbridge No.16929, Royal Flying Corps No. G 21 Hut no. 6 Convalescent Depot,
        A.P.O. S.17, British Expeditionary Force. After I am discharged from here, I shall be sent
        up to the base and then up the line with the best of luck as the Tommies say out here. I am
        hoping to get back to H as I was so happy and with such decent fellows there, but I dont
        think it probable. Lambert, Smith and myself, often used to talk of old times and wondered
        how things were at Paddington. I daresay Gerald, there are not many young fellows left in
        the Audit are there, has Mr Horsley gone? Do drop me a line when you have time, as I assure
        you old boy, it is a real treat to hear Paddington news. <emote type="positive">I have never
            felt in better health</emote>, army life certainly agrees with me also with Lambert.
        Billy Button is at headquarters, got a cushy job. I believe I saw him once there, but I have
        no idea where the other G.W. fellows are. I am afraid I am not very fluent with my French
        yet, I could have done with your services on several occasions. How are Mr Slater and other
        members of the Stats. (or is that department disbanded?) Please remember kindly to them.
        (Lines censored) Cannot stop to write more now as I am just off to a concert in the Y.M.C.A.
        hut in the camp here. (Lines censored) </p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours very sincerely</salute>
        <name type="person">Dick Mansbridge</name>
    </closer>
    <postscript>P.S. I am only about 12 miles from where you used to go to, so perhaps you can guess
        the place I am at, E- s. [Etaples]. Do you ever hear anything of the other boys out
        here?</postscript>
</div>
