Mitchell Library, State Library of New South Wales
Letters to Jack McGrath from William McGrath, 3 January 1915-27 January 1917
MLMSS 9476 / Folder 1 / Item 1
[Page 20]
[Letterhead of 3rd Light Horse Brigade]
8th June 1916.
My dear old Jack & Clare,
Got your (Jack’s) letter of 23 April to day & got one from Clare a couple of weeks ago.
Well I’m glad to see that things are all well so far. Very sorry to hear about Ted & I hope he has fully recovered by this. Also that he was not out of work long through it all. My word the kidlets must be growing. I suppose they are "some" handful by now. Hope the Arbitration award panned out satisfactorily to all concerned.
Give my love to Ede Al & all of the folk. Uncle Will wrote & told me they had had a splendid trip up you way as far as Mt Morgan. He was then off to Mildura for a few days. I wrote you all a post card last week. Remember me to Bob Anderson & tell him I’ll write shortly. My word the works must be like old times with all those hands up there.
I am out in the desert still & at present with another officer & two troops stationed well out. We are having a glorious time as far as soldiering goes, and appear to be quite safe from any attacks. Of course everyone wants something to happen, but that sort of skite comes from the new bloods. All the old hands recognise the good wicket they are on & say nix.
[Page 21]
Our horses are in good nick & get well looked after. The desert sun is very hot but we have managed to get a little shelter rigged here & there, which proves a great boon. Rations are good as can be & we are having a real good turn. Of course we’ve earned it.
I’ve got three splendid nags & you can bet we’re good pals. I’ve picked up a good knowledge of horses here & do some enjoyable rides. We are too far from the canal for swimming but will get a turn there bye & bye.
There have been one or two stunts of which the papers will have published in detail ere this. A week or so ago an aeroplane flew over one of the L.H. camps & dropped fifteen bombs accounting for 9 men & 14 horses killed. It was "No man standing" for a few jiffs. Of course he caught them at stables so was able to do a double shift & get away.
The desert is not very interesting from a physical aspect, but it is marvellous to see the wonderful hiding places to be found everywhere in it. Everything is sand & the wind makes some tremendous mounds & some equally tremendous hollows. I have seen hollows quite two hundred feet deep.
[Page 22]
I saw Walter Barrett but he has gone to France for sure by this. He looked well & was very keen on it. You might remember me to Allie.
Has W.K. arrived that way yet. I’m so sorry all the boys’ got out of work & I guess Mother had a bad time of it. Hope she is alright now. Tell Clare I haven’t had a chance to see that Aunt of hers, but will do so if I get a chance. We are about 50 miles across desert from Port Said, so you see I might see her ere long.
Lizzie is in Adelaide. Her letters are very gloomy, and she seems very dissatisfied all round. I’m very sorry, but we’re in this now till we’re let out, so its about time she got that view of it. She hasn’t been at all short of money in any way & ought to be putting on a brighter face than her letters indicate. Young Will is evidently a boshter.
I got several letters from people in the Hill. One from Geo Robinson containing real spicy congratulation from Jim Hebbard. He reckons I’m right on a royal welcome from him if he ever sees me again, so that was rather cheering.
[Page 23]
Well old man thats’ about all this time. I’ll have such a lot to tell you when I come home that you’ll wish it could have been your luck to come. However your job is at home as I’ve told you in most of my previous efforts. Things are looking bright for me in several ways. When I get back & if they do well both you & Ted will get the call. So in the meantime look well after Clare, the kiddies, & yourself with ever grateful love to you both from
Will.
[Page 24]
[Envelope]
No stamp
A.A.O.
W McGrath
J. P. McGrath Esq.
St Arnaud
Barton St.
Mayfield
Newcastle
N.S.W.
Australia
[Page 25]
[Reverse of envelope]
[Page 26]
22 July 16.
Dear Jack,
Just a note as we are on the move for another camp & things are upside down. Got a letter from you last mail & judge that you have been having a rough time. Gee-whiz but you must have a few howling matches there occasionally.
Hope dear old Clare is OK also Allie K. Give Clare my love. Also tell her that I wrote to Mrs Dye & she has invited me up to Pt Said. As things are now of course I can’t get away just for a while.
We are expecting to be brawling with Johnny Turk & hope to give him a load or two. Things are greatly stirred here just now. Any way, the Devil looks after his own so have no fear & expect a line of more length shortly from your lovingly
Bill.
[Page 27]
[Letter card envelope]
[Printed text]
On Active Service.
Letter Card
For gratuitous distribution among the men at the front.
W McGrath
J. P. McGrath Esq
"St Arnaud"
"Barton Street
Newcastle
N.S.W.
Australia
[Printed text]
God bless our splendid men,
Send them safe home again,
God save our men,
Keep them victorious,
Patient and chivalrous,
They are so dear to us,
God save our men.
[Page 28]
3rd September 1916
My dear old Jack & Clare
Just a short note to let you know I’m still going strong & feeling hale & hearty.
You will have read in the papers during the past few weeks of us having been in a bit of a go & making some captures, well we are still a long way away from any fixed camp or convenience & will probably be in this state for another month. The fighting seems to have settled right out & no Turks about worth speaking of.
We are camped out near to where we had our last fight as our horses couldn’t have gone much further at the pace we had to work. My word it is the first big Light Horse work of the war and it has been most interesting throughout. I only wish we have more stunts like it. Our casualties were not very great & its surprising in open country how much lead it takes to pot a man.
You would like to see the date oases. Just now all the dates are ripe & there are tons & tons everywhere. The country here is soft drift sand for miles & miles & then in the hollows one drops on a clump of palms (4 or 5 acres as a rule). Can get water almost any where at a depth of 2 ft and although brackish quite good & drinkable so you see desert work is not so arduous as the story books make out. Of course there are plenty of drawbacks, but what are we here for?
[Page 29]
Certainly there’s any amount of growling but you can bet your life its not too bad at all, at all.
Got a cheery letter from Ede & Phil the other day. They seem on a good wicket & also mention that things are alright with you & Al. I guess you’re kept busy old man, but keep going. I hope to be a help to you when I get back, which may not be so long now Rumania is in. As for Al & Ted give them my best love & tell them I hope to be able to "do a bit" when I get back.
I wrote to Mrs Dye & got a very kind invitation to Port Said, but owing to being invited on this stunt, I couldn’t get there. I think Mrs Dye will have left for India ere this. She was due to leave about a month ago. I’m sorry as I would liked to have met them.
Give Clare my fondest regards also all the kiddies. My word they must be growing up. Hope Clare is absolutely OK. Also Alice. Got a letter from Vera Godkin. They all seem well. Lizzie is going well & young Will’s last photo showed him as a fine boy. They are in Adelaide.
Well old boss, more later. Paper very scarce just at present. Remember me to Bob and Bess Anderson will you also my old friends. Got a real splendid message from Jim Hebbard & the Central chaps two mails ago.
Well old man you know the good things I wish you both adieu till we meet again
Your ever lovingly Will.
XXXXXXXX
for Clare & the Kiddies
[Page 30]
[Envelope]
Will McGrath
J. P. McGrath Esq
St Arnaud
Barton St
Mayfield
Newcastle N.S.W.
Australia
[Page 31]
[Reverse of envelope]
[Page 32]
26th October 1916.
My dear Jack & Clare,
Got an undated letter from you today but should think it was posted in September.
My word old horse you sound cheerful but you are not having the best of time. However I hope the furnaces are now going O.K. again & things are straightening. I am sending you along a fiver for Xmas & hope it arrives safely to give you & the kids a day out in commemoration.
Dear old Clare I hope she is doing well. I had made full arrangements to call on Mrs Dye but the Turks came & I did not see. I think she has now gone to India but will find out for certain soon as we are now in a camp having arrived here yesterday evening. Its great to be in a tent again & tomorrow I hope to have the luxury of sleeping in a bed even if it is only made of feed-bags. You can guess it will go alright after not having seen one for three months.
Tell Clare she needn’t growl about her luck. We suffer here with too little bed. Glad the kidlets are doing so well. Yes I would like a snap of them very much. Sorry Barrett is wounded & hope its nothing very serious. I had heard about Annie Gainer. Its bad luck but it looks almost like a judgment.
Give my love to Ede & Al & the other tribes. You didn’t mention Al or Ted. Hope they are going alright. Am sending Al along a couple of quidlets for Xmas.
[Page 33]
I am going to a Cavalry School for a course on Monday. Its quite a new thing & at present only meant for senior officers. I feel quite favored at being sent along & you can bet I’m a trier. Will let you know how I get on. Its’ at Cairo.
We are still miles out in the desert so of course it will be quite a good change too. The square head is getting it hot now. Next summer will see it all over. The smaller fry will peter out & then we’ll get the Kaiser’s push. Its just a case of time tells only the push hurts the longer it goes. Jacko has left this country pretty well but he’ll still be a nuisance for some time. They’ll all go though before this time next year.
Well old boss more in a week or so. I may cable or I may post the fiver. Hope it comes in time for Xmas.
Fondest love to you & Clare & the kidlets & all the tribes. Will see you after the war alright. Tooraloo
Yours ever lovingly
Bill
Got a letter from T.A.N.K. in France. He’s alright.
[Page 34]
29th Nov 1916.
Dear Jack & Clare,
I hope you wont mind me the way I send you such spasmodic letters & all that. You cant imagine how things get mixed here & what arrangements we have & their limitations.
Still just a line to let you know I’m living and pretty healthy generally on it. I hope I can say the same in a week or so as we are expecting ‘some’ scrap in a few days & I think its going to be heavy at that. However we’ll wait for it before we say any more. I’m afraid I’m very poor at sending you any description of these things but I’ll tell you all about it when I come back.
Hope everybody is quite well. Your last letter seemed to show you in a bit of a mix up. I was intending to send you a few quidlets as a Xmas cheerer but was unable to do so. Should you want a few quid let Lizzie know. Her last address was B.H. She’ll always do anything possible for you too & you know its your just dues. I think she can manage it alright for you & I am writing her on the subject in case you find it necessary.
Sorry old chapsies to hear of all the bad luck,
[Page 35]
but don’t get downhearted. This will all end soon & things will be alright.
Wait till I come home. You’ll be quite surprised the way things are going to go. So cheers. Hope dear old Clare is up to form again. And also all the kids & Al & Ted & all the others. Tell them some day to expect a letter each, but I don’t know when.
We are continuously moving & life is fairly strenuous. Our horses are getting What Ho’ but they are good stuff & stand well.
Now excuse this note & don’t think I’m shelving any questions from your last letter. Fact is I’ve come out here in such a hurry that I haven’t got any of the old letters here.
Now heaps & heaps of love to you all. You’ll probably get this long after Xmas but lots of fun & a happy New Year.
Yours gratefully
Bill
(Dont forget that par about Lizzie)
[Page 36]
W McGrath
J. P. McGrath Esq.
"St Arnaud"
Barton St.
Mayfield
Newcastle
N.S.W.
Australia
[Text across address]
Eng Drivers Certificates
[Page 37]
[Reverse of envelope]
3rd Light Horse Brigade.
[Page 38]
20th January 1917.
My dear Jack & Clare
It is quite a long time since I wrote you or received any from you. I think I wrote Clare after receiving her boshter cake & I hope you got that alright. I never got Ede’s pudding & whether it fell through the mail-bag or not is a matter of conjecture. Perhaps they thought by the weight it was a bomb or shell & heaved it out of the mail. I believe the maximum weight allowed though is 11 lbs. Still hard luck. It may turn up yet & I am living in hopes.
Glad to see things are brightening again old cock. You are certainly having a very rough time of it. Everybody is but I think you are getting more than your share. However I am very pleased to see you are both as game as ever. Old pals I hope to be a bit of use when I got back & whatever comes my way be sure you are the first for a "cut".
Poor old Al & Ted have been up against it a lot. I must write them today. Both Ede & Nell seem very happy. I often get letters from Morgan now. Vera & Win & Nell all take a turn. Suppose all the kids are quite grown up now & swanky. Would like to see them. You’ve certainly got a crowd round you. How would a farm go? You’d have enough labor to work it.
I often get letters from the firm & think if you care about it I could work the oracle for you when I get back to get fixed up in something good. So keep battling & save those quarter shares of [Tatts?]. Hope you’ve hooked some more ere this.
[Page 39]
We had our last battle in Palestine. Its a wonderful country, what we saw of it. And I would like a chance at getting land there. The horses had a good go in on wheat crops. We lost 4 officers. It makes one think a bit. However I’ve got a good way of standing side on. My name went in for a decoration but dont know if it will come out. Some do & some don’t.
I tried to transfer to the flying Corps but my Colonel wouldn’t stand me. And he wont give me a rise so there you are. Still all good things come to those who wait.
Got a letter from Aunt Molly w.a. & Tommy in France some weeks ago. They both mentioned receiving letters from you. I have written them. Lizzie must be very downhearted. I get very few letters from her lately. 2 in seven weeks. I guess she’s pretty miserable. Think this will end this year. We are doing much more than the papers say in the way of preparation. The Hit of the war will be about May & it will finish one way or other then.
Love to you both & the kidlets. Keep up bravely as you have done, the road is sure to get easier directly
Yours ever lovingly
Will.
[Transcribed by Sandra Mutton for the State Library of New South Wales]

