<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">

    <info>Charles Monaghan</info>
    <!-- This was tagged as <name> which is invalid with the schema. I have changed it to <info> for validation purposes. -->
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1920-07-21"/>
            <name type="place">unknown</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>My beloved Em</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Aye full well this is a week of anniversaries. In addition to the <emote type="positive"
            >wonderful days</emote> of me homecoming it is also the 4th anniversary of the days a
        hundred thousand of us Digger soldiers first smelt war's gunpowder &amp; received our
        baptism of fire. Last Monday the 19th was the anniversary of the Battle of Fromelles when
        the 5th Division got so <factor type="battle">horribly cut up</factor>: then tomorrow the
        22nd , 4 years ago saw the big stunt of Pozieres launched. Shall I ever forget this night
        then, --- the eve of the battle. We were – the stretcher-bearers, mobilised in a village
        about 7 miles behind the line. Darkness fell, &amp; <factor type="prep">each man was ordered
            to stand by to be ready to move off at a moments notice</factor>.</p>
    <p>The preliminary bombardment had already started &amp; we could hear <factor type="sense">the
            shattering roar of the big guns</factor> posted in the rear not far, from where we were.
        After 'standing to', till mid-night, the welcome order came to move forward – welcome only
        because it meant action, the awful waiting &amp; <emote type="negative">period of <factor
                type="prep">inaction</factor> at such times is the thing that tries one's
            nerves</emote>. At daybreak we had reached the area immediately behind the front
        trenches &amp; were at once in the thick of it. The next few hours I have only a <emote
            type="negative">nightmarish remembrance of- I was <factor type="battle">helping poor
                chaps with their awful wounds</factor></emote> (we hadn't got used to them then)
        &amp; getting them back into comparative safety then back again for others. About 10 o'clock
        I met Tony. We were in different units then &amp; hadn't seen each other for weeks. Shall I
        ever forget that meeting. The rivulsion of fooling at seeing a dear familiar face so
        unexpectedly &amp; under such conditions knocked me completely of my perch &amp; I blubbered
        like a kid. I was ashamed but it did me the world of good, the nervous tension was broken,
        &amp; ever after through all the stunt if the next 3 days, I was right as a trivet &amp;
        felt not the strain at all. I wrote to the old cobber last night. Do you wonder how I love
        him?</p>
    <p>Little did we think it possible that 4 years hence we'd be safely back in the homeland
        writing by a cosy fire with nothing more terrifying than the crackling sparks to remind us
        of former fireworks. Then the homecoming last year. Though it was sadly clouded, there was
        that bright single ray, when followed brought me to you. <emote type="positive">Hope burned
            within me</emote> from the time it was illuminated during the period of our
        correspondence, &amp; the first sight of your dear face on that Monday afternoon, set the
        glow of ever, As long as life lasts &amp; in the hereafter Yes, my beloved I thank God for
        all His goodness. 'His mercies endueth forever'. I loved your last letter, Em It breathed
        the pure tender purpose of a high ideal, &amp; together we will strive to attain that lofty
        plane of true &amp; perfect Love. When I revisit the past twelve months my heart overflows
        in a paen of happy rejoicing. It has given me you, the gentlest, sweetest truest &amp; best
        lassie man can be blest with. May I ever be worthy of my great possession. I'll write no day
        by day news this time dear. Will reserve till our next. Good night my love, may sweet sleep
        give you all his rest.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Ever yours</salute>
        <name type="person"> Chas</name>
    </closer>
    <postscript>P.S. Mary arrived home safely yesterday.</postscript>
</div>
