<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Born: 1 April 1893, Regiment: Royal Flying Corps, Regiment number: 16922, Rank: 1st class
        Air Mechanic, Returned to office: 10 March 1919, Retired: Resigned on 25 March 1925. </info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1917-04-26">April 26th</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>

        <salute>Dear Mr Taylor,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>No doubt you think that I have forgotten all about you and my friends of the Audit, but never
        let it be said (this is an army term, if you please.) Truth to tell I have been going to
        write time after time, but have had to put it off for various reasons. I am taking this
        opportunity of writing to you, while I am in charge of tonights guard. I get this job about
        once a week now, its not so bad, I have three men and a man in waiting; we mount at 5pm and
        dismiss at 7am. We make ourselves <emote type="neutral">as comfortable as we can</emote>, in
        the guard tent, which just covers over the top of the sand bags, and these have got grass
        growing out of them now. The sand bags are about 4ft high and make a good protection. April
        1st I got my two stripes up, after being a 1st Air Mechanic for 12 months, the Non-
        Commissioned Officers have a very decent mess here, and everything is ok. I am corporal in
        charge of wireless, photographic, electrical and all instruments used on aeroplanes, I have
        had a very good education on all those subjects, but the one I like best is the wireless,
        its far more interesting than photography, which is a very big thing indeed out here, and a
        lot depends upon a good photograph of the Hun lines</p>

    <p>Yesterday I saw a nice little game between one of ours and one of theirs, after our <factor
            type="battle">anti-aircraft fire</factor> had taken it up a bit higher, our machine went
        for it and got well over the top of it, then two more of ours came along and forced it down,
        she tried all manner of tricks, but down she came alright, and landed a clean machine, not
        broken in any part, and the two Huns inside it quite well. </p>

    <p>We gave a revue (theatrical show) to our chaps here on the 13th, it went off alright, we
        started at 9pm and gave a two hours show, am enclosing programme, and will forward a photo
        of myself as the oldest inhabitant as soon as I receive them from the Frenchman who took
        themKind regards to all of the section and the remainder of the agreements, and hoping you
        are fit and well. Good bye.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours sincerely,</salute>
        <name type="person">F.R. Morris</name>
    </closer>
</div>
