<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Born: 13 September 1888, Joined GWR: 19 May 1904, Regiment: Railway Troop, Royal
        Engineers, Regiment number: 87749, Rank: Sapper, Died: Killed in action on 6 May 1917</info>
    <opener>
        <name type="person">Montague Percy Pond</name>
        <dateline>
            <date when="5 April 1916"/>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>

        <salute>Dear Mr Hunt,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I was very pleased to receive your letter for which many thanks. It took nearly a fortnight
        to reach me as I have changed about a good deal lately from one division to another and it
        has followed me around. I am pleased to say <emote type="positive">I am still keeping very
            fit</emote> and going on in about the same way. I think the last time I wrote we were
        living in trucks. Well we have now moved into huts about ten feet square, which are <factor
            type="conditions">very comfortable</factor> although not quite as large as the trucks.
        They are well built and stand about a foot from the ground so keep very dry. We have two of
        them, one which we use as an office and the other to sleep and live in. We also have a tent
        which we use for keeping kits etc. in, but we shall probably sleep in it when the weather is
        a bit warmer.</p>
    <p>We have had some <factor type="conditions">lovely weather</factor> lately, quite like summer
        but rather cold at night. We had a great deal of snow last month also plenty of rain and
        wind, and were over the tops of our boots in mud. We are stationed at a very small village
        which stands very high (about 600 feet above sea level) you can guess it is a bit breezy at
        times. It is a one-eyed hole with only two cafes and no shops. We have all our meals cooked
        at one of the cafes, and <emote type="positive">we live very well</emote> although there is
        not very much variation in the menu. I have managed to have one or two musical evenings
        lately. The fiddle I bought appears to be a fairly good one but my fingers are not quite so
        nimble as they were. I am afraid I shall have to put in a month or twos practice before I
        get back to where I was before I came out here. Glad to hear you have taken it up again. We
        shall be able to get a band for our next lamb dinner whenever that will be.</p>
    <p>Things do not seem to make much of a move round this way. We get plenty of aeroplanes over
        and see a good many fights in the air. There have also been a good many <factor
            type="battle">shells dropped not very far away from us</factor>, but we have managed to
        dodge them so far although, one of our fellows, who comes from the Midland Railway and who I
        worked with for some time, has been wounded and sent to base. There is only one G.W. man
        anywhere near me as far as I know and that is Colcott from Chief Goods Managers Office but
        he is some distance away and I hadnt seen much of him. I was surprised to hear that Morris
        had gone into the R.F.C. (Royal Flying Corps) after being rejected for the Infantry. I was
        also surprised and sorry to hear about Jack Symons. I had heard nothing about it. How did it
        happen? It must be very quiet at the office now with so many gone. (Censored line). As you
        say it is quite a change from the old days. I have not yet come across any of those who
        joined the R.E. (Royal Engineers) Transport lately. Did you know that Arthur Watton has
        joined?</p>

    <p>We had a concert party belonging to one of the divisions stationed round here, staying in the
        village last week, and they gave us a show two nights running. They had a proper stage with
        scenery and footlights, everything complete. <emote type="positive">They were very good
            indeed</emote>. The programme consisted of songs, sentimental and otherwise, also a
        Sketch and some Charlie Chaplin pictures which were very laughable as usual. Well, I dont
        think I can tell you much more at present. Please remember me to all at the office.</p>
    
    <closer>
        <salute>Kind regards, Yours sincerely,</salute>
        <name type="person">M.P. Pond</name>
    </closer>
</div>
