<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Born: 5 January 1877, Regiment: Railway Troop, Royal Engineers, Regiment number: 138054,
        Rank: Sapper, Returned to office: 5 May 1919</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-04-21"/>
            <name type="place">Salonika, Greece.</name>
        </dateline>

        <salute>Dear Mr Wood,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Just a few lines to let you know I arrived safely after visiting several places which I am
        not allowed to mention. <factor type="sense">This place is quite oriental</factor> as the fronts of the houses are for the
        most part looked after and kept in repair, while the backs are allowed to go, and it gives
        one a shock to see a fine building in the front, and then to go to the back and see it all
        neglected and ready to fall down. It is <factor type = "conditions">very hot here during the day and the swarms of flies
        and mosquitoes keep one very busy</factor> and I <emote type = "negative">dread</emote> to think what it will be like in the summer.
        It seems strange to see oxen drawing carts and donkeys with packs on, but it is a very
        common sight here. I sometimes have to go to the big steamers in a small pinnace [ships
        boat] and when it is rough it requires some nerve to walk along the sides of barges that are
        pitching and tossing and then climb up the ships side by a rope ladder, but it comes easier
        in time. It is<factor type="sense"> very mountainous here</factor>, and <emote type="positive">we get a very fine view of Mount Olympus and the
        snow-capped peaks.</emote> I had to go by motor up country the other day and I had to grip the side
        of the car as <factor type = "conditions">the roads are awful</factor> and sometimes there is only just room for the car to
        travel and a sheer drop on the other side. The labourers at the docks are Greeks and when
        they are taken on in the mornings <emote type="neutral">it is a regular Babel till the Military Policeman <factor type="sense">uses his
        persuader (truncheon)</factor> right and left and that calms them somewhat.</emote> I have not met Mr Cox's
        son yet but should I do so I will make myself known to him. I have had to revert to sapper
        again as there are not sufficient men of our staff for us to remain N.C.O.s but if it is
        brought up to strength I am promised them again. The first person I saw here was Gray of the
        Stats (Statistical Department), and we are working together. Trusting that you are quite
        well and with kindest regards to Messrs Cox, Slater, Rogers and Hunt.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Am yours obediently,</salute>
        <name type="person">D.J. Robertson</name>
    </closer>
</div>
