David Joseph Robertson, 21 April 1916, Salonika, Greece. Born: 5
January 1877, Regiment: Railway Troop, Royal Engineers, Regiment
number: 138054, Rank: Sapper, Returned to office: 5 May 1919
Transcript
Dear Mr Wood,
Just a few lines to let you know I arrived safely after visiting several
places which I am not allowed to mention. This place is quite oriental as
the fronts of the houses are for the most part looked after and kept in
repair, while the backs are allowed to go, and it gives one a shock to see
a fine building in the front, and then to go to the back and see it all
neglected and ready to fall down. It is very hot here during the day and
the swarms of flies and mosquitoes keep one very busy and I dread to
think what it will be like in the summer. It seems strange to see oxen
drawing carts and donkeys with packs on, but it is a very common sight
here. I sometimes have to go to the big steamers in a small pinnace
[ship’s boat] and when it is rough it requires some nerve to walk along
the sides of barges that are pitching and tossing and then climb up the
ship’s side by a rope ladder, but it comes easier in time. It is very
mountainous here, and we get a very fine view of Mount Olympus and the
snow-capped peaks. I had to go by motor up country the other day and I
had to grip the side of the car as the roads are awful and sometimes
there is only just room for the car to travel and a sheer drop on the other
side. The labourers at the docks are Greeks and when they are taken on
in the mornings it is a regular Babel ‘till the Military Policeman uses his
persuader (truncheon) right and left and that calms them somewhat. I
have not met Mr Cox’s son yet but should I do so I will make myself
known to him. I have had to revert to sapper again as there are not
sufficient men of our staff for us to remain N.C.O.s but if it is brought up
to strength I am promised them again. The first person I saw here was
Gray of the Stats (Statistical Department), and we are working together.
Trusting that you are quite well and with kindest regards to Messrs Cox,
Slater, Rogers and Hunt.
Am yours obediently,
D.J. Robertson
