<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
 <info>Born: 30 March 1883, Regiment: Railway Troop, Royal Engineers, Regiment number: 138053, Rank:
  Sapper, Died: 1965</info>
 <opener>
  <name type="person">Mark Anthony Russell</name>
  <dateline>
   <date when="4 February 1916"/>
   <name type="place">France</name>
  </dateline>

  <salute>My Dear Bertie</salute>
 </opener>
 <p> I am pleased to say I am still in the same job and getting to understand the run of things. It
  is very interesting work, as you would imagine. It is a real line here, sometimes <factor
   type="prep">we are pushed and carry on till the early hours of the morning</factor>. I might say
  there is <emote type="neutral">no grumbling about tea money, overtime or bonus quotas</emote>
  putting in as much as eighteen hours a day sometimes and it would not do to send deputations to
  the chief who is also hard at it, in his room; there is a special way of dealing with such in the
  army.</p>
 <p>Of course one never knows how long this may last I may have marching orders to proceed elsewhere
  any day. Each day is absolutely a day unto itself here. We dont count tomorrow. I see you have
  been visited with a blizzard, we also have had <factor type="conditions">a severe touch of
   winter</factor> and at the present moment it is snowing hard outside. The shutters are closed and
  the work is being carried on by lamplight, this is necessary owing to the glass having recently
  left the windows in small fragments some souvenirs [shells] having called upon us. When the
  weather is fine we are fresh air fiends now both day and night except that we close the shutters
  when snowing or raining. The latter it is often doing. There are hosts of interesting things I
  could write you about but these will do later on when I have the pleasure of seeing you. Lieut.
  Duntons crowd was hereabouts, but I did not run up against him.</p>
 <p>I suppose the Derby* entries have commenced to run now. I met another GW fellow the other day,
  Sergeant Gregory, a Slough fellow. I think George Jones would know him. I have seen this fellow at
  Paddington but did not know him to speak to. I had a letter from Longmoor Camp. Must correct
  information. J. Higgs is in the Railway Transport Engineers with another friend of mine, Watton of
  Windsor who was in the Finance office</p>
 <closer/>
</div>
