<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Kenneth William Sharland, 26 July 1917, Pashan Camp, Kirkee, India. Born: 25 September
        1888, Regiment: 1/6 East Surrey Regiment; Bedfordshire Regiment; Bedfordshire and
        Hertfordshire Regiment, Regiment number: 34173; 32376, Rank: Private, Died: Jan-</info>
    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1917-07-26" >July 26th</date>
            <name type="place">India</name>
        </dateline>

        <salute>My dear Mr Biggs</salute>
    </opener>
    <p><emote type="neutral">The writing mood is on me</emote> so I take the opportunity to send
        you a few lines to let you know how I am getting on, at the same time hoping that at some
        future date I may have the pleasure of hearing from you. Your letter is bound to be very
        interesting to me as I have not seen or heard from anybody at Paddington for over six
        months.</p>

    <p>I left Aldershot on March 16th and travelled as far as Durban via Sierra Leone and Cape Town
        on the White Star Liner Suevic. <emote type="positive">This part of the journey was delightful</emote>, the <emote type="positive"><factor type="conditions">food</factor> and
        <factor type="conditions">accommodation</factor> was very good</emote> for a troopship. Of course this is accounted for by the fact
        that it is an Australian troopship. Everything was done that could be to make the journey
        enjoyable for the <factor type="sense">one thousand seven hundred men on board</factor>. We stayed just outside Sierre
        Leone for three days but were not allowed to leave. We arrived at Cape Town on Saturday
        afternoon four weeks after leaving Keyham and had a <factor type="prep">route march</factor> round the town the same
        evening. The next day we were allowed to roam about at will all day and <emote type="positive">a right jolly time
        we had</emote> although it was <factor type="conditions">very hot indeed</factor> for winter. <factor type="sense">Cape Town is a beautiful place</factor> and <emote type="positive">the
        inhabitants made our visit very enjoyable</emote>.</p>

    <p><emote type="positive">The patriotism of the South African is wonderful</emote> to us after the coolness of the English
        (especially Aldershot). On the Monday we sailed for Durban arriving there on the Thursday
        evening after a <factor type="conditions">rather rough journey</factor> round the Cape. We did not land till the Saturday
        afternoon and then bid goodbye to the Suevic. She went on to Australia. We had two weeks at
        Durban and <emote type="positive">had a glorious time in a rest camp</emote> on Ocean Beach. Every day we went <factor type="conditions">bathing</factor> and
        only had <factor type="prep">parades</factor> up to 12 noon each day. The trams were free to us all over the city and
        invitations were showered upon us by the English residents. You can rest assured that we
        were very sorry to leave such a delightful spot, still all good things come to end and we
        finally had to go on board the Laconia belonging to the Cunard company for <emote type="negative">four weeks
        misery</emote>, we lay in the harbour for one week <emote type="negative">longing to go ashore</emote> before we started on the
        last stage of our journey to India. This ship was actually <factor type="conditions">lousy (infested with lice)</factor> and we
        had to put up with a shirt inspection every day. <emote type="negative">The <factor type="conditions">food</factor> was bad and very little of it</emote> and
        to back it all up <emote type="negative">the canteen was rotten as well</emote>. <emote type="negative">I was glad to get to Bombay and get off
        such a <factor type="conditions">rotten ship</factor></emote>. <emote type="neutral">I lost a stone in <factor type="trauma">weight</factor> during that four weeks.</emote></p>

    <p>We arrived in India during the <factor type="conditions">monsoon period</factor> and have <emote type="negative">had plenty of rain more than we like</emote> I
        can assure you.</p>

    <p>Kirkee is only about hundred miles from Bombay and is about six thousand feet above the sea.
        We will while here never have the extremes of weather as the <factor type="conditions">climatic conditions</factor> are
        considered to be ideal here. Strange as it may seem to English people native women do most
        of the work here, and actually act as bricklayers labourers carrying pans of mortar on their
        heads, the men do very little indeed. <factor type="sense">Sunday is the same as any other day to them</factor>. As they
        have their own religious days when they have what they call Ram Jamees. All cartage is done
        by oxen and is rather slow and cumbersome. Kirkee Bazar is about three quarters of an hours
        walk from Pashan Camp and is rather interesting but is very dirty, <factor type="sense">children run about naked</factor>
        and the <factor type="conditions">drainage and dwellings</factor> are very bad indeed. <factor type="sense">Cigarettes</factor> made by the Turkish tobacco
        company Bandra can obtained for eleven annas (former unit of Indian currency) per 100
        (eleven pence) and are very good indeed, being better than the Nebka. Poona is the nearest
        city and is about five miles away. I walked there last Thursday to have a look round, this
        place boasts of one or two hotels and an Italian restaurant but is otherwise an exact
        counterpart of Kirkee and <factor type="sense">quite as dirty</factor>. The Italian restaurant is very good and is quite
        the equal of most London restaurants.</p>

    <p>We do not receive a very many letters out here, as the mail is so uncertain, <emote type="neutral">we never know
        when the next one will arrive.</emote> When you are writing you must let me know all the news, I
        wonder whether your section will ever be established again as it was before. Since I came
        out here I have taken up <factor type="prep">signalling</factor> and find it very useful, there is just a possibility I
        might be able to learn wireless, if so I dont doubt that it might be useful to me, when we
        get back to Blighty if there is half a chance to do so I will cease it.</p>

    <p>Our Battalion is at Aden and unless the signalling alters my destination I will eventually
        find myself there. <emote type="neutral">It is not exactly the place I should choose if I had my own way but of
        course there is no choice about it.</emote> Well I think I have given you all the news now and am
        sure you are tired of reading this letter by now, so will close with best wishes to you all
        from,</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>yours sincerely,</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Kenneth W. Sharland</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
