<text>
    <div type="letter">
        <personal_info>Kenneth William Sharland, 26 July 1917, Pashan Camp, Kirkee, India. Born: 25
            September 1888, Regiment: 1/6 East Surrey Regiment; Bedfordshire Regiment; Bedfordshire
            and Hertfordshire Regiment, Regiment number: 34173; 32376, Rank: Private, Died:
            Jan-</personal_info>
        <opener>
            <dateline>
                <date>Mar 1967</date>
                <name type="place">India</name>
            </dateline>

            <salute>My dear Mr Biggs</salute>
        </opener>
        <p>The writing mood is on me so I take the opportunity to send you a few lines to let you
            know how I am getting on, at the same time hoping that at some future date I may have
            the pleasure of hearing from you. Your letter is bound to be very interesting to me as I
            have not seen or heard from anybody at Paddington for over six months.</p>

        <p>I left Aldershot on March 16th and travelled as far as Durban via Sierra Leone and Cape
            Town on the White Star Liner Suevic. This part of the journey was delightful, the food
            and accommodation was very good for a troopship. Of course this is accounted for by the
            fact that it is an Australian troopship. Everything was done that could be to make the
            journey enjoyable for the one thousand seven hundred men on board. We stayed just
            outside Sierre Leone for three days but were not allowed to leave. We arrived at Cape
            Town on Saturday afternoon four weeks after leaving Keyham and had a route march round
            the town the same evening. The next day we were allowed to roam about at will all day
            and a right jolly time we had although it was very hot indeed for winter. Cape Town is a
            beautiful place and the inhabitants made our visit very enjoyable.</p>

        <p>The patriotism of the South African is wonderful to us after the coolness of the English
            (especially Aldershot). On the Monday we sailed for Durban arriving there on the
            Thursday evening after a rather rough journey round the Cape. We did not land till the
            Saturday afternoon and then bid goodbye to theSuevic. She went on to Australia. We had
            two weeks at Durban and had a glorious time in a rest camp on Ocean Beach. Every day we
            went bathing and only had parades up to 12 noon each day. The trams were free to us all
            over the city and invitations were showered upon us by the English residents. You can
            rest assured that we were very sorry to leave such a delightful spot, still all good
            things come to end and we finally had to go on board the Laconia belonging to the Cunard
            company for four weeks misery, we lay in the harbour for one week longing to go ashore
            before we started on the last stage of our journey to India. This ship was actually
            lousy (infested with lice) and we had to put up with a shirt inspection every day. The
            food was bad and very little of it and to back it all up the canteen was rotten as well.
            I was glad to get to Bombay and get off such a rotten ship. I lost a stone in weight
            during that four weeks.</p>

        <p>We arrived in India during the monsoon period and have had plenty of rain more than we
            like I can assure you.</p>

        <p>Kirkee is only about hundred miles from Bombay and is about six thousand feet above the
            sea. We will while here never have the extremes of weather as the climatic conditions
            are considered to be ideal here. Strange as it may seem to English people native women
            do most of the work here, and actually act as bricklayers labourers carrying pans of
            mortar on their heads, the men do very little indeed. Sunday is the same as any other
            day to them. As they have their own religious days when they have what they call Ram
            Jamees. All cartage is done by oxen and is rather slow and cumbersome. Kirkee Bazar is
            about three quarters of an hours walk from Pashan Camp and is rather interesting but is
            very dirty, children run about naked and the drainage and dwellings are very bad indeed.
            Cigarettes made by the Turkish tobacco company Bandra can obtained for eleven annas
            (former unit of Indian currency) per 100 (eleven pence) and are very good indeed, being
            better than the Nebka. Poona is the nearest city and is about five miles away. I walked
            there last Thursday to have a look round, this place boasts of one or two hotels and an
            Italian restaurant but is otherwise an exact counterpart of Kirkee and quite as dirty.
            The Italian restaurant is very good and is quite the equal of most London
            restaurants.</p>

        <p>We do not receive a very many letters out here, as the mail is so uncertain, we never
            know when the next one will arrive. When you are writing you must let me know all the
            news, I wonder whether your section will ever be established again as it was before.
            Since I came out here I have taken up signalling and find it very useful, there is just
            a possibility I might be able to learn wireless, if so I dont doubt that it might be
            useful to me, when we get back to Blighty if there is half a chance to do so I will
            cease it.</p>

        <p>Our Battalion is at Aden and unless the signalling alters my destination I will
            eventually find myself there. It is not exactly the place I should choose if I had my
            own way but of course there is no choice about it. Well I think I have given you all the
            news now and am sure you are tired of reading this letter by now, so will close with
            best wishes to you all from,</p>
        <closer>
            <salute>yours sincerely,</salute>
            <signed>
                <name type="person">Kenneth W. Sharland</name>
            </signed>
        </closer>
    </div>
</text>
