<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Hugh Andrew Skilling, 5 January 1917, France. Born: 17 April 1891, Regiment: 3 Battalion
        Bedfordshire Regiment; 7 London Brigade Field Artillery, Regiment number: 43228, Rank: Lance
        Corporal, Died: 1970</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1917-01-05">January 5, 1917</date>
            <name type="place">Somme, France</name>
        </dateline>
        <name type="place">unknown</name>
        <salute>Dear Mr W.H. Davies,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Just a line to let you know I have not forgotten you. I received a <factor type="sense">letter</factor> on Tuesday 3rd of
        January 1917 which you sent to me on August 24th 1916. By the marking on the envelope it has
        been round to various regiments and officers, but it has arrived quite safe at last. I
        received the <factor type="sense">letter</factor> you wrote in October quite safe. <emote type="neutral">I am sorry I have not written before
        but we were rather busy when I received your last letter and we could not send more than a
        <factor type="sense">field card</factor> for about a month.</emote> <emote type="positive">Well I am pleased to tell you that I am still going on first
        rate.</emote> I expect you will be surprised to hear that I have left the Northamptonshire Regiment
        and am now attached to the Army Printing and Stationary Services. We are opening a new
        branch in the photography line and I am here as a <factor type="prep">photographer</factor>.</p> 
        
        <p>I am unable to tell you more than this up to the present. I expect Harry will be pleased to hear this as he used to give
        me quite a lot of tuition in this respect.</p>

    <p>There are only two of us here up to the present and <emote type="positive">as the <factor type="conditions">dark rooms</factor> are not finished yet we
        are having an easy time.</emote> The Officer is away in England just now getting some more
        photographic apparatus so we are on our own and I am in charge.</p>

    <p><emote type="positive">We are <factor type="conditions">billeted</factor> with a company of Australian electricians, mechanics, mining and boring
        engineers and are having a fine time.</emote> There are a good lot of fellows and make us very
        welcome. <emote type="positive">We had a grand Xmas with them and they know how to enjoy themselves.</emote> You can
        understand what a change this is after being <factor type="battle">in the line</factor>. Just before I came on this job we
        had over a month <factor type="battle">in and out of the line</factor> waiting to <factor type="battle">go over the top</factor> when the <factor type="conditions">weather</factor> was
        favourable.</p>

    <p>We went in for four days then out for a rest for about three days then back again. The <factor type="conditions">water
        was over our knees</factor> in the <factor type="battle">trenches</factor> and it was <emote type="negative">impossible to use the <factor type="battle">communication trenches</factor>
        at all.</emote> We were holding the <factor type="battle">front line</factor> with <factor type="battle">two platoons</factor> (I should say our boys section of
        the line). <factor type="sense">Our platoon was twenty two strong</factor> including the Officer, and during the
        bombardment we had <factor type="trauma">eight put out in ten minutes</factor>. There were <factor type="conditions">no dugouts of any description</factor>
        there, so you can imagine what it was like to <factor type="conditions">stand there for four nights</factor>. <emote type="negative">We hoped the
        <factor type="conditions">weather</factor> would be alright so that we could <factor type="battle">go over and get it done with</factor> but it was not to be.</emote>
        We were out <factor type="prep">digging</factor> one night when they let us have it for five hours with <factor type="battle">gas shells</factor>, we
        had <factor type ="trauma">two chaps hit with them and put right out.</factor></p>

    <p><emote type="negative">The <factor type="sense">sights and smells</factor> were awful, as a good many of the <factor type="sense">chaps lay just as they fell</factor> during
        the advance.</emote><emote type="negative"> It was impossible to <factor type="battle">bury</factor> them.</emote> Also there were about a <factor type="sense">dozen dead horses round</factor>
        about in the mud that were killed by <factor type="battle">shell fire</factor> while bringing up <factor type="battle">ammunition for the guns</factor>.
        Our <factor type="battle">guns</factor> never cease down there, as soon as one section stop, another lot open out so you
        can tell there is Somme noise.</p>

    <p>The last time we came out, was for <factor type="conditions">forty eight hours rest</factor> then <factor type="battle">in again and over</factor>, but the
        <emote type="negative">troops were in such a <factor type="trauma">bad condition</factor> that the doctor sent in a report saying we were not fit
        for the line</emote> so two other regiments in our division went over in our place.</p>

    <p><emote type="positive">We were held in reserve and I am glad to say not required after all.</emote> Well I think this is
        about all, for now, I have been with the A.P. &amp; S.S. since December 1st and I can tell
        you, I hope I shall stop here.<emote type="neutral"> I have no desire to go back to the line.</emote> Kindly remember me
        to all old friends. With kind regards to yourself and all on Section 4.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours sincerely,</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person"> H.A. Skilling</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
    <postscript>No. 2 Section Advanced Section Army Printing &amp; Stationary Service</postscript>
</div>
