<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Arthur Smith, 19 November 1916, Addington Park War Hospital, England. Born: 8 March 1895,
        Regiment: Railway Troop, Royal Engineers, Regiment number: 87760, Rank: Lance Corporal,
        Returned to office: 16 June 1919, Retired: 30 September 1955</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-11-19">November 19th</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
    </opener>
    
    <p>I expect you wonder what has become of me as you have not heard from me for such a long time.
        The reason is that since the 20th September I have been <factor type= "trauma">suffering with enteric (typhoid)</factor>.
        The exact diagnosis of my case being <factor type="trauma">para typhoid B</factor>. I have not been up three weeks until
        next Friday, but <emote type="positive">since I first got out of bed I have made splendid progress.</emote> I was in an
        <factor type="conditions">isolation hospital in France</factor> for six weeks and previous to that <factor type="conditions">in a General Hospital</factor> for
        eight days. <emote type="positive">I arrived here late last Wednesday night after a very decent journey.</emote> This is a
        <factor type="sense">beautiful palace surrounded by a park</factor> in which we can walk about and we are allowed to go to
        the post office which is quite near. <emote type="positive">I am quite happy and comfortable here, it is a <factor type="conditions">splendid
        hospital</factor>.</emote> We have a <factor type="sense">concert or cinema nearly every night</factor> in the big hall. <factor type="conditions">Food is good</factor> and
        plentiful. <emote type="neutral">How long it will be before I am considered fit again I have no notion</emote>, as a rule
        it takes months for a person to get right again.</p>
    
    <p><emote type="negative">It is a very funny and beastly complaint.</emote>  <emote type="positive">During to the whole time I have <factor type="conditions">been in hospital</factor> I
        have received every attention and kindness.</emote> During the months of July and August <emote type="negative">when I was
        in the Somme district I had a very rough time</emote>, was <emote type="negative">nearly worked to death</emote> and had <factor type="conditions">little
        sleep</factor>. At one period we had to commence work at 2am but we were supposed to rest in the day
        but we could not get any. <emote type="positive">However, it was all in a good cause and we got through it.</emote>
        Ambulance trains were loaded up at the station where I was and <factor type="sense">we saw some awful sights</factor>.
        <factor type="trauma">English and German wounded</factor>. Perhaps I <factor type="trauma">picked my fever up</factor> at this place, but one never knows.
        While I was in the <factor type="conditions">isolation hospital</factor> in France I was kept for three weeks and two days on
        liquids but <emote type="positive">I am pleased to say that the doctor has now put me on ordinary diet.</emote> With the
        kindest regards and best wishes to all,</p>
    
    <closer>
        <salute>I remain yours obediently.</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">A. Smith</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
