<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../date_schema.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Sidney Smith, 19 March 1916, France. Born: 20 October 1881, Regiment: Railway Operatives
        Division, Royal Engineers, Regiment number: 218849, Rank: Sapper, Returned to office: 19 May
        1919, Retired: 20 October 1941</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-03-19">March 19th</date>
            <name type="place">unknown</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>My Dear Elton and all,</salute>
    </opener>
    
    <p>I expect you are wondering why I have never written since leaving England. Well the fact is I
        have never had a chance for <emote type="neutral">it has been a Cooks Tour since I was last with you.gi</emote> Perhaps I
        had better try and give you some idea of my adventures from the time we last met. It was not
        many hours after seeing you all that we were dispatched for France. We landed at a town
        <emote type="positive">after a nice long trip.</emote> <emote type="negative">At this spot, a rest camp so called,</emote> we spent about a week. What
        with <factor type="prep">parades</factor> in the daytime for various reasons and <factor type="prep">employed at the docks</factor> all night,
        <factor type="prep">unloading flour</factor> was the job that came my way <emote type="negative">you can imagine the rest we had.</emote> However we
        then went on to another base and here owing to <factor type="trauma">illness</factor>, we were all <factor type="conditions">isolated</factor> for ten days
        and no letters could be sent. Within a day or two of being released from this I alone of all
        our boys was packed off to another depot so that was the last I have seen for the time being
        of our crowd, and have been on my own since. After a couple of nights at this depot I was
        sent to a point to <factor type="prep">get experience in the work</factor> I came here for. <emote type="positive">This turned out to be the
        best thing I had touched</emote> for the staff were billeted out and I slept in a <factor type="conditions">feather bed</factor> which
        was great for it was <factor type="conditions">under canvas</factor>.<emote type="positive">I soon found out that my luck was in and that happiness and comfort would be my lot</emote> whilst
        there. <emote type="negative">Alas my dream was soon dispelled</emote>, and after a week of civilised existence, I was sent
        for by the depot. After another 48 hours there I was sent away again to some other spot, but
        en route, was detained at a rest camp for two days, apparently owing to the <factor type="conditions">absence of 
        trains</factor> to the point I was going.</p>

    <p>Covered vans are used here to convey soldiers about. Strange to say the actual truck I made
        this last journey in I saw again the next day <factor type="sense">loaded with sick horses</factor>, so being used for any
        purpose you can guess they cannot be compared to the carriages in which we made our daily
        trips to town and back. To continue my travels, the next day I was sent to the point I am
        now writing from, and which I think will be my residence for some little time as I have now
        taken up <factor type="prep">regular duties</factor>. <emote type="negative">It is a terrible, Godforsaken and desolate spot.</emote> There is naught to
        be seen except <factor type="battle">shell holes</factor> and <emote type="negative"><factor type="conditions">rats</factor> and these latter are an abomination.</emote> <emote type="neutral">There is little to
        be heard here at night except <factor type="battle">gun fire</factor> and <factor type="conditions">rats</factor> and one soon gets used to both.</emote> I went to a
        village, the nearest here, about two miles away, on Sunday last and <emote type="negative">it was really an awful
        sight to see how it had been smashed by <factor type="battle">shell fire</factor>.</emote> You can now I trust realise the reason
        for my not writing before, in fact I have only written to my wife and father, and have only
        received one letter from each of them and that was a few days ago. I can tell you that <emote type="neutral">I
        hunger for news of home</emote> after being here a month without a word. It is also almost <emote type="negative">impossible
        to buy anything for there is nowhere to get it.</emote></p>

    <p>I trust all is well with everyone at 164 and that poor old Sid is alright again. If Miss
        Welshs little affair has come off I wish her the very best of luck and trust she will have
        all happiness. Please write to me soon some of you. Lots of luck, and good wishes to you all. </p>
    
    <closer>
        <salute>Your old pal,</salute>
        <signed>
            <name type="person">Sid</name>
        </signed>
    </closer>
</div>
