<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Sidney Smith, undated, Longmoor Camp, England. Born: 20 October 1881, Regiment: Railway
        Operatives Division, Royal Engineers, Regiment number: 218849, Rank: Sapper, Returned to
        office: 19 May 1919, Retired: 20 October 1941</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="unknown">unknown</date>
            <name type="place">unknown</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Mr Beak and all,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>My address shows you I am well in now. <emote type="negative">Oh it is a different life and comes hard at first</emote>,
        <factor type="conditions">four blankets on the floor</factor> and it is hard. I didnt get used to it until last night which was
        my first nights proper rest. <emote type="negative">The food is fair but served very rough and not enough </emote>after the
        <factor type="prep">drills</factor> you have to go through. The <factor type="conditions">weather</factor> has of course been very bad and I am <factor type="conditions">still in the
        same things</factor> as I left London last Monday. <emote type="negative">I look like a tramp</emote> and my collar, of the colour,
        something like the office grate. I was <factor type="trauma">inoculated</factor> last Thursday but <emote type="neutral">was not so bad but some
        of the fellows felt it.</emote> I expect I shall have a time with the next lot but hope I dont as
        they have not got much sympathy and <emote type="negative">of course there is no comfort</emote>. A lot of fellows (about
        four hundred and fifty) have been shifted (Saturday and today) to Bordon and we shall all
        probably go when we get <factor type="prep">fitted out</factor> as they are making a new camp there with three new
        companies. <emote type="negative">It cannot be worse than here which is very dreary and lonely</emote> and the nearest
        village (Liss) is three miles away where several of us went on Saturday and Sunday and had
        tea. That place is I may say, truly rural. I have had a <factor type="sense">military hair cut</factor> tonight and feel
        that I look like Bill Sykes. <emote type="negative">I am afraid none of our young ladies would care to be seen
        walking up number 1 (platform at Paddington Station) with me as I look at the moment.</emote>
        (censored.)</p>

    <p>There is no leave now, only when you get your overseas leave which is generally after six
        weeks here and <emote type="negative">when you come back you are the put on the draft so it isnt long is it?</emote> George
        Jones and Isles will probably stay longer as they are to have false teeth but me, although
        as you know, I have got a very <factor type="trauma">bad lot of teeth</factor> was passed and they are not touching mine.
        Army ways are funny and I have already found out a lot of which I trust I shall one day be
        able to tell you.</p>

    <p>I forget to tell you we all got split up into different huts when we arrived and mine is
        about a mile away from the camp. <emote type="positive">It is very comfortable however much better <factor type="conditions">accommodation</factor>
        than at the camp.</emote> Three other of our fellows were put in there with me and I found some
        others, also some very nice London &amp; North Western Railway chaps, one of whom knew Mr
        Bryant and all the Fares office chaps. He was the head of the Season Ticket Office at
        Euston. I might say that <emote type="positive">they have been very good to me and assisted me more than some of
        our chaps</emote>, one or two of whom I am sorry to say have not done what they might to assist
        others and I (together with some of the others) have been surprised but of this more anon
        when we meet. Well I bid you all adieu for the present. I think of you all often and only
        <emote type="negative">wish I was back again</emote> <emote type="neutral">but it has to be done and one can only hope the end will come soon.</emote> I
        hope poor old Syd Douce is getting on alright as we have not heard how he is. Now good luck
        to you all and every success and tell them all that could go <emote type="negative">to keep out of this life as
        long as they can.</emote> Goodnight.</p>

    <p>I may say that four of our chaps who were lucky to get their outfit last week were moved to
        Bordon this afternoon: G. Holloway, Isles, Borrough, G.R.J. Jones.</p>

    <closer>
        <salute>Yours very sincerely,</salute>
        <name type="person">S. Smith.</name>
    </closer>
</div>
