Sidney Smith, undated, Longmoor Camp, England. Born: 20 October
1881, Regiment: Railway Operatives Division, Royal
Engineers, Regiment number: 218849, Rank: Sapper, Returned to
office: 19 May 1919, Retired: 20 October 1941
Transcript
Dear Mr Beak and all,
My address shows you I am well in now. Oh it is a different life and comes
hard at first, four blankets on the floor and it is hard. I didn’t get used to
it until last night which was my first night’s proper rest. The food is fair
but served very rough and not enough after the drills you have to go
through. The weather has of course been very bad and I am still in the
same things as I left London last Monday. I look like a tramp and my
collar, of the colour, something like the office grate. I was inoculated last
Thursday but was not so bad but some of the fellows felt it. I expect I
shall have a time with the next lot but hope I don’t as they have not got
much sympathy and of course there is no comfort. A lot of fellows (about
four hundred and fifty) have been shifted (Saturday and today) to Bordon
and we shall all probably go when we get fitted out as they are making a
new camp there with three new companies. It cannot be worse than here
which is very dreary and lonely and the nearest village (Liss) is three
miles away where several of us went on Saturday and Sunday and had
tea. That place is I may say, truly rural. I have had a military hair cut
tonight and feel that I look like Bill Sykes. I am afraid none of our young
ladies would care to be seen walking up number 1 (platform at
Paddington Station) with me as I look at the moment. (censored.)
There is no leave now, only when you get your overseas leave which is
generally after six weeks here and when you come back you are the put
on the draft so it isn’t long is it? George Jones and Isles will probably stay
longer as they are to have false teeth but me, although as you know, I
have got a very bad lot of teeth was passed and they are not touching
mine. Army ways are funny and I have already found out a lot of which I
trust I shall one day be able to tell you.
I forget to tell you we all got split up into different huts when we arrived
and mine is about a mile away from the camp. It is very comfortable
however much better accommodation than at the camp. Three other of
our fellows were put in there with me and I found some others, also some
very nice London & North Western Railway chaps, one of whom knew Mr
Bryant and all the Fares office chaps. He was the head of the Season
Ticket Office at Euston. I might say that they have been very good to me
and assisted me more than some of our chaps, one or two of whom I am
sorry to say have not done what they might to assist others and I
(together with some of the others) have been surprised but of this more
anon when we meet. Well I bid you all adieu for the present. I think of
you all often and only wish I was back again but it has to be done and
one can only hope the end will come soon. I hope poor old Syd Douce is
getting on alright as we have not heard how he is. Now good luck to you
all and every success and tell them all that could go to keep out of this
life as long as they can. Goodnight.
I may say that four of our chaps who were lucky to get their outfit last
week were moved to Bordon this afternoon: G. Holloway, Isles, Borrough,
G.R.J. Jones. Yours very sincerely,
S. Smith.
