<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- source:http://www.u.arizona.edu/~rstaley/wwlettr1.htm -->
<letter>
    My Dearest Mary,
    I write this on board a boat that will leave for overseas soon. Our letters are all censored from now on so there is no use wasting my time and the censor's trying to tell you some things.
    I took in a little of New York last night. I went into the city from Long Island by the way of the tube under the Hudson River. I got out at the Pennsylvania station and spent the rest of the night to 1:30 a.m. just looking around. There wasn't any chance to go to a good show because you know how the advance sales take everything. Harry LauderA British singer noted for his comic stage persona. is at the Metropolitan and I would certainly like to have seen him.
    I saw where the film "The Beast of Berlin" was being shown and right across the street was Arthur Guy Empey, "Over the Top."A Broadway show based on a best-selling book.
    The city is full of soldiers and sailors all the time, I guess. Anyway there were a good many last night.
    The city is an easy place to get lost because of the irregularity of the streets. Most all streets out our way cross each other at angles but in N.Y. they may take any direction. I walked down one street and when I took a notion to turn and go back, I wasn't on the same street at all and I couldn't tell where I made any turn.
    I got a good look at the city from the waterfront today. It was a bright clear day and we could see quite a distance. I have seen pictures of N.Y. from the Hudson and I can say that the real thing was just a picture laid before you. I would like to have stayed at Camp Mills until I had seen more of the city but the powers that be see otherwise.
    I can scarcely realize we are going. Everything moves off without any trouble or delay that it might just as well be a trip up the river.
    Well, I have been looking forward to this for quite a while and I guess, now that the time for going has come, it fits right into my scheme and ways of thinking that the going seems only a small part of it.
    Well, I must close so as to mail this right away so, goodbye little girl for a time at least. Keep on writing.
    With truest love, Lloyd M. Staley
    My address: Co. K, 137 Infantry, American Expeditionary Forces
</letter>
