<?xml-model href="file:/C:/Users/AMC343/OneDrive%20-%20University%20of%20Pittsburgh/Documents/Slav2550/ww1-project/letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Gilbert Williams, 6 April 1916, France. Born: 18 April 1894, Regiment: 1/6 Seaforth
        Highlanders, Regiment number: 2175, Rank: Private, Died: 1967. Note: Williams also fought in
        Second World War returned from war on 15 November 1948</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-04-06">April 6th</date>
            <name type="place">unknown</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear Mr Hunt,</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Thanks very much for your letter which I received a week or two ago, also for the
        magazine.</p>
    <p>We are in the <factor type="battle">trenches</factor> just now. In fact <emote type="negative">we seem to spend about three times as much time in
        as we do out.</emote> Also we are in a pretty <factor type="battle">warm spot</factor>, it was about here, towards the end of last
        summer that the French and German had some of the fiercest fighting of the war. The country
        around about is a <factor type="battle">veritable maze of trenches</factor>. <emote type="negative">The fighting at one time was so fierce that
        there was only time just to bury the dead</emote> in the sides of the trenches, and now that the
        <factor type="conditions">trenches have crumpled</factor> one is constantly <factor type="sense">seeing the bones of mens legs or their boots</factor>, or
        <factor type="sense">skulls</factor> sticking out from the sides of the trenches, pleasant, eh? <emote type="negative">There will be a pleasant
        smell here in the summer.</emote> <emote type="neutral">I only hope we are not here then.</emote> In places we are only about
        twenty yards away from Fritz and company. Consequently all times the air is pretty thick
        with <factor type="battle">bombs</factor>, <factor type="battle">grenades</factor> and <factor type="battle">trench mortars.</factor></p>

    <p>These last are pretty hellish sort of toys. They have <factor type="sense">an explosion like about ten earthquakes</factor>
        rolled into one. <emote type="negative">But even these are not the worst we have to put up with.</emote> The trenches being
        so close together there is of course any amount of <factor type="battle">mining</factor> going on. <emote type="neutral">So one never knows when
        the particular lump of earth one is standing on is going to take a trip through the solar
        regions.</emote> When a <factor type="battle">mine</factor> does go up, <emote type="negative">there is some excitement knocking about I can tell you.</emote>
        Suppose for instance we were going to explode one, all the <factor type="battle">artillery</factor> in the neighbourhood is
        ranged on the spot and directly the <factor type="battle">mine is exploded</factor>, there is hell let loose on the crater.
        Of course as soon as he gets the range the <factor type="battle">enemy replies</factor>, so that <factor type="sense">the air is fairly full of
        everything that kills quickly</factor>. <emote type="negative">One can on these occasions always rely on a good many
        casualties.</emote> Since we have been in this spasm there have been <factor type="battle">five exploded</factor> in this
        neighbourhood, while others are expected to go up at any time. <emote type="neutral">So much for conditions
        here.</emote></p>

    <p>How is everything in town? Pretty quiet I suppose. I see youve had the zepps (Zeppelins) over
        again? Is it a fact that one dropped in the Thames? (Lines censored.) That is about all the
        news, so will close, kindest regards to everybody.</p>
    <closer>
        <salute>Yours very sincerely,</salute>
        <name type="person">Gilbert Williams</name>
    </closer>
</div>
