Gilbert Williams, 6 April 1916, France. Born: 18 April
1894, Regiment: 1/6 Seaforth Highlanders, Regiment
number: 2175, Rank: Private, Died: 1967. Note: Williams also fought in
Second World War returned from war on 15 November 1948
Transcript
Dear Mr Hunt,
Thanks very much for your letter which I received a week or two ago, also
for the magazine.
We are in the trenches just now. In fact we seem to spend about three
times as much time in as we do out. Also we are in a pretty warm spot, it
was about here, towards the end of last summer that the French and
German had some of the fiercest fighting of the war. The country around
about is a veritable maze of trenches. The fighting at one time was so
fierce that there was only time just to bury the dead in the sides of the
trenches, and now that the trenches have crumpled one is constantly
seeing the bones of men’s legs or their boots, or skulls sticking out from
the sides of the trenches, pleasant, eh? There will be a pleasant smell
here in the summer. I only hope we are not here then. In places we are
only about twenty yards away from Fritz and company. Consequently all
times the air is pretty thick with bombs, grenades and trench mortars.
These last are pretty hellish sort of toys. They have an explosion like
about ten earthquakes rolled into one. But even these are not the worst
we have to put up with. The trenches being so close together there is of
course any amount of mining going on. So one never knows when the
particular lump of earth one is standing on is going to take a trip through
the solar regions. When a mine does go up, there is some excitement
knocking about I can tell you. Suppose for instance we were going to
explode one, all the artillery in the neighbourhood is ranged on the spot
and directly the mine is exploded, there is hell let loose on the crater. Of
course as soon as he gets the range the enemy replies, so that the air is
fairly full of everything that kills quickly. One can on these occasions
always rely on a good many casualties. Since we have been in this spasm
there have been five exploded in this neighbourhood, while others are
expected to go up at any time. So much for conditions here.
How is everything in town? Pretty quiet I suppose. I see you’ve had the
zepps (Zeppelins) over again? Is it a fact that one dropped in the
Thames? (Lines censored.) That is about all the news, so will close,
kindest regards to everybody. Yours very sincerely,
Gilbert Williams.
