<?xml-model href="file:/C:/Users/AMC343/OneDrive%20-%20University%20of%20Pittsburgh/Documents/Slav2550/ww1-project/letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Francis Witt, 28 May 1916, Salonika, Greece. Born: 8 February 1893, Regiment: Royal
        Engineers, Mediterranean Expeditionary Force; transferred to Office of Superintendent of
        Line on 15 June 1914, Regiment number: 138069; WR296343, Rank: Sapper, Died: 1970</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-05-28">May 28th</date>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>Dear G. [Mr Burgoyne],</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I guess you wonder what has become of me after this long silence, but you will see I am a
        good distance away from the homeland now. I arrived here early in April and <emote type="positive">since the start
        have been getting on quite well.</emote> You may be interested to know that Gray from your
        department is also here. It is rather strange that I should rub against him.</p>

    <p>The <factor type="conditions">weather is brilliant</factor>, cloudless skies day after day, but it is <factor type="conditions">very hot</factor>. There are plenty
        of <factor type="conditions">mosquitoes</factor> about. They are very tantalising. A net is practically a necessity for
        sleeping purposes. I am billeted in a warehouse, it is a <factor type="sense">very old place</factor>, and has stood
        hundreds of years. I should think, according to its general appearance.</p>

    <p>I have not picked up the lingo yet, but French is chiefly spoken, and <emote type="neutral">I much regret not
        having studied it more when I had the opportunity at home.</emote> This town is a queer sort of
        place as compared with some of the French towns we know, and am sure <emote type="negative">I shall not wish to see
        it again when once I leave.</emote> The cafs are not so gay as the French, but <emote type="positive">I manage to have fun
        occasionally.</emote> We have got a <factor type="conditions">piano and gramophone</factor> to amuse ourselves with. I hope we shall be
        able to have another trip to Paris, when the war has cleared up, but of course when is a
        question nobody can answer yet awhile. Shall be very pleased to hear some news of you, and
        conclude now with all the best.</p>

    <closer>
        <salute>Yours sincerely,</salute>
        <name type="person"> Frank</name>
    </closer>
</div>
