<?xml-model href="../letter_sample_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<div type="letter">
    <info>Frederick G. Woodhams, 16 February 1916, France. Regiment: 13 London Rifles, Regiment
        number: 1383, Rank: Private; Lance Corporal; Sergeant, Died: Killed in action on 16 August
        1917, having been struck by shrapnel; prior to this, he had been wounded twice. These are
        typed extracts of a letter that Frederick Woodhams had written to his family (RAIL 253/516).
        Below that is an article from the Illustrated London News, 1915 (ZPER 34/146s9</info>

    <opener>
        <dateline>
            <date when="1916-02-16"/>
            <name type="place">France</name>
        </dateline>
        <salute>--</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>The last time I wrote I think I told you <emote type="neutral">we had lost our comfortable job on railheads</emote>. We
        have been shifted from General Headquarters and are at the most godforsaken hole there can
        possibly be in France. <emote type="negative">We had a rotten journey <factor type="conditions">raining</factor> all the time.</emote> Reveille* was at 4am
        and we eventually left the station about 10am. The accommodation consisted of the <factor type="conditions">old cattle
        trucks</factor>, and <factor type="conditions">rations of bully and biscuits</factor>. It was a <factor type="conditions">very cold and uncomfortable journey</factor>. We
        arrived at our destination about 4.30pm and after standing in the <factor type="conditions">rain</factor> for 2 hours with full
        pack on, we set out on a <factor type="prep">ten mile march</factor>. <emote type="negative">Its the worst march Ive ever done.</emote> The majority of
        us at the finish were absolutely knocked up and were only too glad to crawl into the billets
        before going to bed, which was about 12pm. They gave us a <factor type="conditions">mug of tea</factor> (the first we had since
        six in the morning) and best of all a <factor type="conditions">ration of rum</factor>. The up to date soldier kit to carry
        about from place to place consists of 150 rounds of ammunition, inside the pack; overcoat,
        fur coat, two pairs socks, one pants, one shirt, ground sheet, iron rations [emergency food
        supply]. Outside pack; Mackintosh and mess tin, in haversack; cleaning kit, hold all, 24lbs
        rations, soap and towel, and on top of that extras such as handkerchiefs, plate, mug,
        tobacco, etc, two smoke helmets* in a satchel slung over the shoulder, a respirator in the
        left flap of a tunic and field dressing on the right, and of course the rifle, <factor type="sense">in all its no
        light weight on a long march</factor>, it takes all ones strength and staying power to keep going. </p>

    <p>We are billeted in a barn and have <factor type="conditions">a sea of mud</factor> to get through. We have no boards, <factor type="conditions">so sleep
        on the ground</factor>, fires are not allowed in the billet and at night time its <factor type="conditions">devilish cold</factor>. In
        the village there is a <factor type="sense">little general shop</factor> (now nearly sold out), one pub where they sell
        something they charge 2d for and call beer, there are no shops of any description and of
        course no amusements. <emote type="negative">Rations are not so good now </emote>(todays dinner, Sunday, bully beef, stew
        and two potatoes between 35 men. We have a loaf and a bit (small loaf) and two tins of jam
        between seven men, the <factor type="conditions">short bread issue</factor> being augmented by the <factor type="conditions">world famous army biscuits</factor>.
        Our captain is a perfect gentleman and about the most popular man in the regiment, the
        junior captain (an absolute sport) and the platoon officers are all very decent sort of
        fellows. <emote type="positive">We appear to be much better off in this respect than before</emote>, and certainly think
        that D. Co. has got as good a selection of officers as any other company in the battalion.
        One of our fellows ran across a number of Audit R.E.s and they enquired after Maggs and
        myself. </p>
    <closer>
        <name type="person">Freddy </name>
        <salute>or Whats left of him after some very stiff marching.</salute>
    </closer>
</div>
